<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress</link>
	<description>Development live!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 04:35:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.2.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 23 January 2015</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-january-2015</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-january-2015#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 04:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3073</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! The newest changes, organized by a completely arbitrary and arguably meaningless set of priorities: Major: Shoals tides have been reworked: they now shift only between shallow water &#038; land, never creating or destroying deep water tiles. They also move fifteen times faster. New fake language: &#8216;butt&#8217;. To quote the purpose statement of the [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! The newest changes, organized by a completely arbitrary and arguably meaningless set of priorities:</p>
<ul>
<li>Major:
<ul>
<li>Shoals tides have been reworked: they now shift only between shallow water &#038; land, never creating or destroying deep water tiles. They also move fifteen times faster.</li>
<li>New fake language: &#8216;butt&#8217;. To quote the purpose statement of <a href="https://code.google.com/p/buttbot/">the original</a>:
<p>Buttbot is a social experiment in humour and interaction, it<br />
    playfully mocks those around it. Almost deconstructionist in<br />
    nature by manipulating the context of the text it parodies,<br />
    it forces people to reexamine what has been said in a new light.</p>
<p>    It builds on the tradition of mechanising surrealist techniques,<br />
    such as example Dadadodo by Jwz implementing the cut-up technique<br />
    made famous by William S. Burroughs (and used by Radiohead).<br />
    However instead of merely rearranging the content, buttbot aims<br />
    to augment it with the simplistic low brow humour.</p>
<p>    The use of puerile humour is mainly to bring the conversation<br />
    back down to earth, to remind us that in our intellectual pursuits<br />
    that childish references to anatomy can bring a smile to our<br />
    faces&#8230;</li>
<li>Fake languages are now stackable. Try adding &#8220;fake_lang = dwarven,!!!&#8221; to your rcfile, or see the <a href="http://s-z.org/neil/git/?p=crawl.git;a=blob_plain;f=crawl-ref/docs/options_guide.txt;hb=HEAD">options guide</a> for more languages and options.</li>
<li>New rcfile option: &#8220;easy_door&#8221;, which toggles whether or not to ask for a prompt when (C)losing doors if only one open door is adjacent. (For consistency.) Defaults to true.</li>
<li>add_autopickup_func() rcfile functionality has changed; returning false now signifies that corresponding items should never be picked up. I am told that if your autopickup is broken by this, you should do the following: &#8220;in the function passed to add_autopickup_func, change return false to return nil and change return a and b or c and d to return (a and b or c and d) or nil&#8221;. If you don&#8217;t understand that (I&#8217;m not super confident on it myself), maybe just delete the relevant functions and hope for the best.</li>
<li>Evocables now charge &#038; discharge per-type, rather than individually. (That is, whenever you use a lamp of fire, all lamps of fire are unuseable until you gain enough xp to recharge it.) The elemental spirits are whimsical beings&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Moderate:
<ul>
<li>Light armour now has a small penalty to spellcasting success chance, and heavy armour&#8217;s penalties to spellcasting are slightly reduced.</li>
<li>Bucklers now have a very slightly smaller encumbrance penalty.</li>
<li>Shields&#8217; evasion penalties, &#038; the skill required to completely mitigate them, are now displayed in their descriptions.</li>
<li>Caustic shrikes, after being nerfed, buffed, nerfed, and nerfed, have been buffed. Specifically, they&#8217;re now somewhat buffer, and less likely to appear when polymorphing earlier, weaker creatures. Celebrate!</li>
<li>Natasha has traded her Mephitic Cloud for Conjure Flame, which she&#8217;ll use to try to block off the player&#8217;s avenues of manuever. (She had a bad habit of walking into her own mephitic clouds. Ridiculous cat&#8230;)</li>
<li>All book tiles have been completely replaced.</li>
<li>New tiles for several uniques. Check out Nikola&#8217;s new look, just before the next time he electrocutes you to death!</li>
<li>Gargoyles, being statues, can no longer cast Statue Form.</li>
<li>Exploration piety no longer scales by the size of the level; it now is based solely on the number of tiles explored. (Early Ziggurat levels no longer give enormous amounts of Ash/Nemelex piety.)</li>
<li>Throwing net range no longer varies by the size of the player; all races can now throw them to the edge of LOS, up from 5 squares for most races, 6 squares for ogres, 4 for halflings &#038; kobolds, &#038; a mere 3 squares for spriggans.</li>
<li>The Tome of Destruction has been utterly destroyed.</li>
<li>All non-permanent summoned monsters are now unable to use stairs.</li>
<li>Trog&#8217;s wrath summons are now permanent.</li>
<li>rPois- items now prevent the player from reaching rPois+.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Minor:
<ul>
<li>Item descriptions no longer claim that rPois- &#8220;protects against poison&#8221;.</li>
<li>It is no longer possible to instantly die from putting on a -hp item, or from having your last maximum hit point rotted away, or by being tormented at 1 hp while at rN-.</li>
<li>You can no longer drink !poison, !decay or !degeneration if you know what they are and are not immune to them. Crawl does <b>not</b> encourage self-destructive drinking among its players.</li>
<li>Hell rats no longer appear in the Sewers.</li>
<li>Hexes with a 100% success chance should no longer fail.</li>
<li>+Twstr and +-HP have been removed from randart generation.</li>
<li>Artefacts can no longer spawn with both &#8220;cause random teleportation&#8221; and &#8220;prevent all teleportation&#8221; properties.</li>
<li>Mummies can no longer be trapped in an infinite loop when calling for merchants.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-january-2015/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 15 January 2015</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-january-2015</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-january-2015#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 04:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Your changes for today: Random artefact generation has been reworked. Artefact property distribution is now considerably more structured, and there&#8217;s now a weak correlation between bad &#038; good properties (an artefact with a few good properties is now less to have bad ones, and vice versa). New, rare property: +Twstr, which, when evoked, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Your changes for today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Random artefact generation has been reworked.
<ul>
<li>Artefact property distribution is now considerably more structured, and there&#8217;s now a weak correlation between bad &#038; good properties (an artefact with a few good properties is now less to have bad ones, and vice versa).</li>
<li>New, rare property: +Twstr, which, when evoked, summons a hostile twister nearby. Its winds shred everything nearby &#8211; including you, if you&#8217;re not light on your feet!</li>
<li>Other new properties: Regen+, HP+-, MP+-, rPois-, rN-, and probably a few others I&#8217;m forgetting.</li>
<li>Artefact stats now range +-2-6, up from +-1-5.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Acid walls now display the &#8216;acid floor tile&#8217; all around themselves, even when outside Slime. Should help discourage a few accidental acid deaths&#8230;</li>
<li>Irradiate now has an animation &#8211; console-only for now, until I make some decent tiles for it.</li>
<li>When following Ashenzari, (p) now sacrifices one scroll at a time, and tells you which scrolls were created.</li>
<li>Gozag food shops are now 2/3rds as pricey.</li>
<li>Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace no longer hurls hundreds of corpses across the floor (visually). Maximum five animated corpse movements per casting. Sorry (?), zig-spammers. (The actual functionality of the spell is unchanged; this is just visual.)</li>
<li>Applying Excruciating Wounds and Warp Weapon in succession (in either order) no longer permanently changes weapons&#8217; brands.</li>
<li>Good news &#8211; &#038;^Ib works again!</li>
<li>Invisible giant eyeball messages have been disambiguated.</li>
<li>Confused terrified fungi stumble around.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-january-2015/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 7 January 2015</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-january-2015</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-january-2015#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3064</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! First changes of the new year: Blurry vision&#8217;s effect has been reduced; it now adds a delay of 0.5/1/2 turns (by mutation level), down from 1/2/3. It should now be possible to safely cancel controlled &#038; semicontrolled blink in most situations. New rcfile option, fail_severity_to_confirm, allowing you to set a threshold of spell [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! First changes of the new year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blurry vision&#8217;s effect has been reduced; it now adds a delay of 0.5/1/2 turns (by mutation level), down from 1/2/3.</li>
<li>It should now be possible to safely cancel controlled &#038; semicontrolled blink in most situations.</li>
<li>New rcfile option, fail_severity_to_confirm, allowing you to set a threshold of spell failure rates above which the game will warn &#038; prompt you before casting. The default is to prompt at dark red failure (very high to guaranteed).</li>
<li>Hydra form now only gives +30% HP (down from +50%), and gives half as much healing when devouring enemies.</li>
<li>Gargoyles no longer get 4 less AC from Statue Form than every other race.</li>
<li>Various new tiles, mainly for uniques: check out Eustachio&#8217;s sweet &#8216;stache the next time you see him!</li>
<li>The demonic rune now has a random tile.</li>
<li>Baileys have had their oriflamme replaced with a portcullis.</li>
<li>?/I now lists the contents of decks.</li>
<li>The deck of oddities is now documented in-game.</li>
<li>The deck of summonings has been renamed; it is now the deck of summoning.</li>
<li>Yaktaurs are now slightly more dangerous.</li>
<li>Wasp monsters have been renamed: red wasps are now known as &#8216;hornets&#8217;, and yellow wasps are now just &#8216;wasps&#8217;.</li>
<li>Boring beetles can no longer teleport onto the player in D:1.</li>
<li>There&#8217;s a commit here which uses the word &#8220;retrogdorise&#8221;, and I&#8217;m gonna be honest, I don&#8217;t care about what the commit does. I&#8217;m not even gonna read it. I just wanted to share that with you.</li>
<li>Held weapons no longer apply their brands to thrown weapons.</li>
<li>rElec now protects against lightning.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-january-2015/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 31 December 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-31-december-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-31-december-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 21:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3056</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Last changelog of the year: New trap: the Shadow Trap, appearing from d:3 downward. Any non-summoned creature that moves into it will summon a small group of shadow creatures from the current level, which are always hostile to the player. Traps are now more common in most parts of the game, and considerably [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Last changelog of the year:</p>
<ul>
<li>New trap: the Shadow Trap, appearing from d:3 downward. Any non-summoned creature that moves into it will summon a small group of shadow creatures from the current level, which are always hostile to the player.</li>
<li>Traps are now more common in most parts of the game, and considerably less common in Slime.</li>
<li>Elemental evocables now stack.</li>
<li>?/ has been considerably improved, and a new ?/c(L)oud option has been added.</li>
<li>When examining features with clouds over them, both the description of the feature &#038; the cloud are now displayed.</li>
<li>Maxwell&#8217;s Patent Armour has been moved back toward its old egos; it now has rCorr rElec instead of Resistance.</li>
<li>Cleaving&#8217;s damage to secondary targets has been reduced from 75% to 70%.</li>
<li>A number of rock wall tiles have been replaced or reworked; in particular, Sewers no longer have acid wall tiles.</li>
<li>Megazigs no longer sometimes place the player in the centre of the floor.</li>
<li>The MP cost of the wand-power mutation has been halved; it now costs 3 MP per wand use per level, down from 6.</li>
<li>Ru now applies antimagic to enemies, rather than Muting them.</li>
<li>Dithmenos no longer sometimes considers steam to be a source of fire.</li>
<li>Ironheart Preservers now have significantly worse defenses, but significantly more HP. This may make it worthwhile to bother actually attacking them.</li>
<li>Call Imp now becomes stronger at high power, instead of becoming weaker.</li>
<li>Linux and OS X no longer double all numpad inputs.</li>
<li>?/K no longer lists the skills &#8220;Stabbing&#8221;, &#8220;Traps&#8221;, &#8220;rat&#8221;, and &#8220;bat&#8221;.</li>
<li>Chokoban has been upgraded.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-31-december-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 23 December 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-december-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-december-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 04:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3052</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Another quiet week: Spells &#038; abilities that check enemy MR now display their success chance in the targeting interface. Examining monsters&#8217; spells now allows you to see their chance of affecting you with MR-checking spells. Ru&#8217;s Draw Out Power drain has increased by 20%, and the odds of Apocalypse applying status effects has [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Another quiet week:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spells &#038; abilities that check enemy MR now display their success chance in the targeting interface.</li>
<li>Examining monsters&#8217; spells now allows you to see their chance of affecting you with MR-checking spells.</li>
<li>Ru&#8217;s Draw Out Power drain has increased by 20%, and the odds of Apocalypse applying status effects has increased from 3/5 to 3/4.</li>
<li>Troves that ask for the Horn of Geryon now actually take it, instead of just requesting that you present it.</li>
<li>Ashenzari no longer suppresses blurry vision.</li>
<li>Hydra Form&#8217;s duration has been increased considerably; it&#8217;s now roughly the same as Blade Hands&#8217;.</li>
<li>Dragon Form no longer enhances Dragon&#8217;s Call.</li>
<li>The rock walls of the stone huts in Shoals:5 now actually look like rock in Tiles.</li>
<li>Elemental weapon brands now only have their damage multiplied by 1.5x for each level of negative resistance the target has (e.g. rC-), down from 2x. This is consistent with the extra damage that all other sources of elemental damage get.</li>
<li>Orcish allies no longer cast Animate Dead for Beoghites.</li>
<li>The Iron Rod&#8217;s scaling with spellpower has been considerably reduced; it probably no longer one-shots the toughest monsters in the game.</li>
<li>The Arc Blade&#8217;s discharge effect has been fixed; it now arcs repeatedly to multiple targets rather than only affecting one, making it considerably more powerful.</li>
<li>Sif now gives penance for destroying books, again.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling, and enjoy the holidays!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-december-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 15 December 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-december-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-december-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 03:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3048</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! It&#8217;s been a quiet week for changes: Monster spells can now be examined through the xv screen, in the same way as with books &#038; rods (that is, by hitting a letter corresponding to the spell). At present, this lets you see the description and range of their spells. Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace has been [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! It&#8217;s been a quiet week for changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Monster spells can now be examined through the xv screen, in the same way as with books &#038; rods (that is, by hitting a letter corresponding to the spell). At present, this lets you see the description and range of their spells.</li>
<li>Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace has been reworked; the rate at which corpses fall off is now based purely on the number currently stacked on the player, and spellpower instead increases the amount of AC+SH per corpse, from a base of 0.5 AC+SH per corpse to a cap of 1.5 AC+SH at the new max of 100 power. Skeletons now count the same as other corpses for Cigotuvi&#8217;s purposes.</li>
<li>Gell&#8217;s Gravitas now has a small chance of confusing creatures pulled by it, based on spellpower and on victims&#8217; MR.</li>
<li>A new &#8220;item_slot&#8221; rcfile has been added, to allow you to specify which letter correspond to which items by default. Works like the spell_slot option.</li>
<li>Quite a lot of tiles have been tweaked; notably the Singularity &#038; Sublimation of Blood spell icons, but also many many monsters, which now incorporate advanced artistic techniques such as &#8216;perspective&#8217;. Check out hippogrives!</li>
<li>Xom&#8217;s mood meter has been added to webtiles.</li>
<li>Shard shrike packs can no longer spawn as hell effects in Cocytus; in general, the Cocytus hell effect spawn list has been reworked.</li>
<li>Lava snakes can spit again. (They accidentally lost the ability to spit several months ago.)</li>
<li>Chaos Champions can no longer give the player Resistance for 4000 turns.</li>
<li>Gyre &#038; Gimble can now strike up to 16 times in a single attack. (With the help of the Blade card.)</li>
<li>Artefacts may now again be named &#8220;of the Doge&#8221;.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-december-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 8 December 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-december-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-december-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 05:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Some fun new toys to play with this week: New artefact: Gyre and Gimble, two quickblades linked by a chain. It takes two hands to wield, but strikes twice for every attack. Dual-wielding is finally here&#8230;&#8230;&#8230; New spell: Gell&#8217;s Gravitas, L6 Hexes/Translocations. Targets a creature &#038; hurls all other nearby creatures toward it, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Some fun new toys to play with this week:</p>
<ul>
<li>New artefact: Gyre and Gimble, two quickblades <a href="http://i.imgur.com/5dflcKs.png">linked by a chain</a>. It takes two hands to wield, but strikes twice for every attack. Dual-wielding is finally here&#8230;&#8230;&#8230;</li>
<li>New spell: Gell&#8217;s Gravitas, L6 Hexes/Translocations. Targets a creature &#038; hurls all other nearby creatures toward it, causing damage to whichever ones collide. &#8220;Basically a one-turn Singularity&#8221;.</li>
<li>The &#8216;blurry vision&#8217; mutation no longer causes scroll-reading to occasionally fail. Instead, it adds a delay before the player finishes reading the scroll (and gains the benefits): one turn per level of the mutation.</li>
<li>All non-shortblade weapons now stab equally well (or poorly), excepting felid claws, which now stab as well as shortblades. Clubs no longer have a chance of confusing &#8216;stabbed&#8217; enemies. Ogre Enchanters and Assassins no longer start with clubs.</li>
<li>Armour penalties to dodging have been smoothed; there is no longer a breakpoint at which Dodging goes from giving zero EV to the normal rate. Instead, armour decreases the rate at which Dodging gives you EV. Sample numbers are <a href="http://pastebin.com/nKt9dqJH">here.</a></li>
<li>The Book of Wizardry has been removed; its spells have been redistributed.</li>
<li>Monsters created by Phantom Mirrors are now only two-thirds as strong as the original.</li>
<li>Orange rats have been renamed to hell rats, and are now demonic. They also glow in the dark.</li>
<li>The arbalest &#8220;Hellfire&#8221; has had its hellfire-explosion damage roughly doubled.</li>
<li>When active, Gozag&#8217;s gold now sparkles.</li>
<li>It is once again possible for bardings of flying to generate, after they were accidentally removed earlier this year.</li>
<li>Orc wizards can no longer confuse the player for 30+ turns.</li>
<li>The lords of Pandemonium can now buzz and croak.</li>
<li>Players in hell can no longer hear gut-wrenching screams while Silenced.</li>
<li>Goblins no longer continue their peaceful slumber after being hurled through the air.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-december-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 2 December 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-2-december-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-2-december-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 03:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3035</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Last week was a little quieter, possibly because of some of our US devs visiting friends and family for the holiday weekend, rather than toiling away in the Crawl mines as they know they should. Still, a few changes to report: Potions of confusion have been befuddled out of existence. In their place [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Last week was a little quieter, possibly because of some of our US devs visiting friends and family for the holiday weekend, rather than toiling away in the Crawl mines as they know they should. Still, a few changes to report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Potions of confusion have been befuddled out of existence. In their place sit Potions of Ambrosia, which grant considerable health &#038; magic regeneration for a short period, along with confusion. If the confusion is prevented (by e.g. clarity) or cured, the regeneration immediately ends.</li>
<li>Liches (and their ancient &#038; antique friends) now have a much wider variety of spells available, rather than being restricted to a handful of spellbooks.</li>
<li>Singularity is now considerably stronger at low spellpower, and less powerful at very long range.</li>
<li>Makhleb now gives somewhat more piety for kills, and no longer accepts corpse sacrifice.</li>
<li>Xom now has a &#8216;mood meter&#8217;, looking suspiciously like the piety meter for other, more boring gods. (And yet somehow different&#8230;)</li>
<li>Gozag&#8217;s &#8220;shining gold&#8221; visual effect is now only present on the tile of the gold itself, rather than on surrounding tiles. In console, it&#8217;s now a different colour from normal gold.</li>
<li>Gozag&#8217;s &#8220;duplication&#8221; ability can now duplicate stacks of items.</li>
<li>A wide variety of quotes have been added, mainly for spells.</li>
<li>Pandemonium lords now come in a riotous variety of colour; they have a number of new tiles, and their text descriptions now match up with the tiles.</li>
<li>The Plane Papyrus has been renamed to the Akashic Record.</li>
<li>Various other tile tweaks; all potion tiles have been replaced, goblins &#038; pals were reworked, the Seraph is now considerably taller, and wretched stars now have a worrying glow about them, among other changes.</li>
<li>Irradiate now offers a warning before harming allies.</li>
<li>The game no longer crashes whenever the player takes cloud damage.</li>
<li>Delayed Fireball is now back to being two schools, after a brief, yet torrid romance with the mysterious &#8220;Utility&#8221; school.</li>
<li>It is no longer possible to hit monsters so hard that their souls are completely obliterated.</li>
<li>Messaging has been improved for attempting to close doors on Orbs of Destruction.</li>
<li>Orb spiders no longer have poisonous bites.</li>
<li>Trees can no longer enter malign portals.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-2-december-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 25 November 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-25-november-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-25-november-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 05:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3030</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! This week has been simply magical, by which I mean, full of spells. New spells. Two new spells. And a bunch of other changes: New spells: Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace, a L5 Necromancy spell that turns corpses into temporary AC &#038; SH. The corpses slowly slough off over time &#038; (sometimes) when the player is [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! This week has been simply magical, by which I mean, full of spells. New spells. Two new spells. And a bunch of other changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>New spells:
<ul>
<li>Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace, a L5 Necromancy spell that turns corpses into temporary AC &#038; SH. The corpses slowly slough off over time &#038; (sometimes) when the player is hit or blocks an attack. Found in the Book of Unlife and (sometimes) in Kikubaaqudgha&#8217;s second gift.</li>
<li>Singularity, a L9 Translocations spell that summons an all-devouring interdimensional maw. Nearby enemies are sucked inward &#038; damaged, moreso the closer they get. Found in the Plane Papyrus, a high-level Translocations book containing Dispersal, Controlled Blink, Malign Gateway, Disjunction, and of course Singularity. (Various other books have been adjusted slightly.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Force Lance is now L4 Conjurations/Translocations, slightly more accurate, and better at knocking back enemies. Flying enemies are especially vulnerable.</li>
<li>Dispersal now affects a wider area, and has a chance of confusing affected creatures.</li>
<li>Twisted Resurrection has been removed.</li>
<li>New enemies:
<ul>
<li>Robin of the Strong Arm, a hobgoblin unique appearing in the very early Dungeon. She&#8217;s stronger than your average hobgoblin, and accompanied by her own personal army of hobgoblins &#038; goblins, the latter of which she will happily hurl at her enemies. Duck!</li>
<li>Shard Shrikes, batty monsters that appear in Cocytus. They spit Throw Icicle, resist and attack with cold, and flock in small bands. They have 2 AC, but are only <i>literally</i> made of glass in certain non-canonical fanfictions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Seraphim are now considerably more dangerous: damage doubled, speed increased by 50%, and a new spellset, including Hunting Cry, Summon Holies, Injury Bond and Cleansing Flame.</li>
<li>Seraphim now occasionally appear on the orb run.</li>
<li>Ghost crabs have scuttled sideways all the way from Crypt to Swamp.</li>
<li>Insubstantial wisps are now slightly more fragile &#038; less numerous, but have Static Discharge.</li>
<li>Hellwings now have Cigotuvi&#8217;s Embrace, and spawn with it active.</li>
<li>If the player clears a ziggurat and enters another, they may occasionally find themselves in the center of the floor rather than the edge. The odds of this increase with depth and number of ziggurats cleared.</li>
<li>Zin&#8217;s Recite is no longer usable if no enemies with low enough HD are visible. Recite invulnerability is now mentioned in monster descriptions.</li>
<li>Gozag will no longer offer the player shops that are entirely useless for their race.</li>
<li>Ctrl-direction now always attacks, rather than sometimes opening or closing doors, or removing traps.</li>
<li>In Zot Defense, the player can now place traps on top of other traps.</li>
<li>Butchering and bottling blood now only takes a single turn.</li>
<li>Powered by Death now works with all corpses.</li>
<li>The Wild Magic card now afflicts enemies with miscast effects, rather than the player, and restores the player&#8217;s MP for each enemy affected. It&#8217;s moved from the Deck of Punishment (back to) the Deck of Wonders.</li>
<li>When in shadow form, the player can no longer be petrified.</li>
<li>Monsters can no longer block their own attacks.</li>
<li>Butterfly colours have been disambiguated.</li>
<li>The legendary weapons &#8220;Glorpy&#8221;, &#8220;Loopy&#8221;, and &#8220;Plog&#8221; may now appear.</li>
<li>Gozag&#8217;s shopkeepers have had their genders randomized.</li>
<li>Insects are no longer referred to as &#8216;she&#8217;.</li>
<li>Electric golems can no longer breathe.</li>
<li>Monsters no longer believe that rN+ armour allows them to see invisible.</li>
<li>Angels no longer have demonic powers.</li>
<li>Bats can now memorize spells.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-25-november-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 17 November 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-17-november-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-17-november-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 07:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Lots of fun changes this week: Enemy-held weapons now have their brands ID&#8217;d on sight. The Death Knight background has been removed. New item: the Iron Rod, which fires a spray of shrapnel in a wide arc. Extremely effective against agile, low-AC enemies, but ineffective against armoured enemies or at a distance. Nemelex [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Lots of fun changes this week:</p>
<ul>
<li>Enemy-held weapons now have their brands ID&#8217;d on sight.</li>
<li>The Death Knight background has been removed.</li>
<li>New item: the Iron Rod, which fires a spray of shrapnel in a wide arc. Extremely effective against agile, low-AC enemies, but ineffective against armoured enemies or at a distance.</li>
<li>Nemelex &#038; deck changes:
<ul>
<li>New cards:
<ul>
<li>Elements, which summons three beasts of the four elements.</li>
<li>Rangers, which summons two or three ranged-missile users.</li>
<li>Placid Magic, which removes all status effects and applies heavy antimagic to all creatures in sight, including the user. (Dazing enemy spellcasters as if they&#8217;d been hit with antimagic weapons repeatedly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Revamped destruction cards:
<ul>
<li>Storm has replaced rain and swiftness with summoning air elementals, an elemental wellspring, or thunder clouds alongside a wind blast.</li>
<li>Pain has lost Torment; it can now instead summon flay your foes alive.</li>
<li>Venom has lost Sting for earlier Venom Bolts and Poison Arrows, but at low power will briefly make the user vulnerable to poison.</li>
<li>Degeneration now applies a temporary malmutated effect to targets, along with polymorphing them to creatures with lower HD. Undead are dazed.</li>
<li>Vitriol now can provide Corrosive Bolts at higher power.</li>
<li>Orb bursts will now attempt to home on monsters they might reasonably hit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Revamped battle cards:
<ul>
<li>Potion has strictly-negative effects taken out, and will also apply its effects to allies if possible.</li>
<li>Blade now solely gives a cleaving status. It doesn&#8217;t stack with the reaching of polearms or the original cleaving of axes, but otherwise applies to all forms of armed &#038; unarmed combat.</li>
<li>Helm can apply Stoneskin or Shroud of Golubria effects to allies at high power.</li>
<li>Elixir gives a small amount of temporary vitality to your allies, alongside its restorative effects to the user.</li>
<li>Shadow gives the darkness status (reduced LOS) instead of invisibility.</li>
<li>Dowsing is now significantly stronger in duration and range.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Revamped summoning cards:
<ul>
<li>Pentagram now summons a more constrained set of demons (stronger at lower power and weaker at high power), and an additional accompanying hell hound, rakshasa, or <b>pandemonium lord</b>.</li>
<li>Dance has replaced its short swords with quarterstaves and its dire flails with executioner&#8217;s axes. It also has a chance of summoning a randart.</li>
<li>Foxfire has lost butterflies and gained ravens.</li>
<li>Repulsiveness can now summon both an ugly thing and a very ugly thing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Revamped emergency cards:
<ul>
<li>Cloud surrounds all hostile monsters with varying types of clouds, instead of randomly scattering clouds in all valid places in sight.</li>
<li>Shaft now randomly places shafts under other monsters as well.</li>
<li>Tomb can now raise rock walls on stone stairs and deep water.</li>
<li>Velocity will always apply a overall-positive effect (with allies present).</li>
<li>Banshee now drains victims, in addition to causing fear.</li>
<li>Solitude can now cause Disjunction at high power.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Dowsing is no longer in the deck of battle.</li>
<li>Decks of war have lost their set of destruction cards.</li>
<li>The Cloud card has moved from decks of destruction to decks of emergency.</li>
<li>Mercenaries now have slightly better kit, and mercenaries that your god would dislike are not offered.</li>
<li>In general, cards that your god would dislike will have their dislikeable effects suppressed. (E.g., Venom for TSO.)</li>
<li>Removed cards: Metamorphosis, Herd, Bones.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Monster tweaks:
<ul>
<li>Draconian &#038; deep elf knights are considerably stronger (and have had their spell sets changed up).</li>
<li>Caustic shrikes are now a little weaker and a little rarer.</li>
<li>Revenants are no longer affected by Silence.</li>
<li>Enemy necromancers can now cast Inner Flame.</li>
<li>Pan Lord spells have been considerably reworked.</li>
<li>Anubis Guards now have Control Undead.</li>
<li>Hell Beast HD, AC, and EV are no longer randomized (and are set to the max value they could have had before). Their speed is still randomized.</li>
<li>Sphinxes are now sometimes (presumably) androsphinxes.</li>
<li>Basilisks are now little.</li>
<li>Green rats are now known as river rats. Beware their swimming prowess&#8230;!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>All gods now give piety for kills made by followers (undead and otherwise) in the exact same way as for kills made by the player.</li>
<li>Vampires now bottle blood with (c), instead of (a)(a). They can now bottle blood from level 1 onward.</li>
<li>Different types of melee attacks (slashing, piercing, blunt, etc) no longer cause different amount of noise. (Melee noise still varies by damage done.)</li>
<li>Summon Greater Demon now provides a more() by default when the summoned demon stops being charmed.</li>
<li>Ziggurats now have a reliable supply of restore abilities potions, and a very small number of beneficial mutations potions.</li>
<li>The rod of striking has been removed.</li>
<li>Monsters now return to their original forms in death. (Like poor Prince Ribbit.)</li>
<li>Runed doors &#038; Lugonu&#8217;s Corruption are now noted in level annotations, by default.</li>
<li>Ctrl-f can now find runed doors.</li>
<li>Qazlal&#8217;s Disaster Area is now stronger at low invocations.</li>
<li>Felid Monks have been buffed.</li>
<li>Mimics are now immune to telepathy.</li>
<li>High-pitched whines have been removed.</li>
<li>The game will no longer claim that skeletons can be bottled.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-17-november-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 11 November 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-november-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-november-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 05:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! More behind-the-scenes work this week (we&#8217;ve finally switched to C++11!), not so many new features. Still, we&#8217;ve got a few: Gozag changes: Monsters slain while following Gozag will now always drop gold if they would normally have a chance of leaving a corpse. Gold from monsters now depends significantly less on their body [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! More behind-the-scenes work this week (we&#8217;ve finally switched to C++11!), not so many new features. Still, we&#8217;ve got a few:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gozag changes:
<ul>
<li>Monsters slain while following Gozag will now <b>always</b> drop gold if they would normally have a chance of leaving a corpse.</li>
<li>Gold from monsters now depends significantly less on their body mass.</li>
<li>Gozag shop item quality has been considerably improved.</li>
<li>Food has been moved from a potion petition (porridge/blood) to a guaranteed food shop offer in each use of Call Merchant. Vampires get blood shops; Ghouls get corpse shops. (Butchers?)</li>
<li>Potion Petition no longer contains negative effects.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Potions of blood no longer give nutrition to non-vampires.</li>
<li>Porridge has been removed.</li>
<li>Okawaru no longer asks for corpse sacrifice; piety from kills has increased, and piety loss over time has decreased.</li>
<li>Followers of Kikubaaqudgha and Nemelex Xobeh now get their respective special titles when their highest skill is Necromancy or Evocations (respectively).</li>
<li>Snake now has an extremely cool set of new mosaic floor tiles &#8211; check them out!</li>
<li>In Dis, the Serpent of Hell now has a reaching attack. Other Serpents of Hell have been weakened slightly.</li>
<li>Players&#8217; movement speed now maps directly to their ghosts&#8217; movement speed, rather than action speed. (E.g., spriggan ghosts or ghosts of characters wearing boots of running now only travel faster, rather than also attacking, spellcasting, etc faster.)</li>
<li>Condensation Shield is now melted when blocking a fire attack, not when failing to block one.</li>
<li>The player can now be corroded when blocking an attack with a shield.</li>
<li>The Transparent Skin mutation now gives -enemy accuracy at all levels, not just at level 3.</li>
<li>Killer Klowns corpses are now as colourful in death as they were in life.</li>
<li>Anubis Guards will no longer be slain by the traps of the Tomb they guard. (Likewise, Death Scarabs.)</li>
<li>Monsters that aren&#8217;t Donald can now talk outside Dungeon. (Fixing a bug introduced in January of 2010.)</li>
<li>Ghosts in console are no longer represented by &#8216; &#8216;.</li>
<li>Insults have been considerably improved, you decrepit pissant boot-licking toady!</li>
<li>Cats now like fish.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
<p>(And be sure to check out our <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/new-servers">new servers</a>, if you missed them last week.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-november-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New servers!</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/new-servers</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/new-servers#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 04:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the last year, a whole host of new servers have come online for play. CKR, in Korea. Webtiles only. CBRO, in Georgia, USA. Webtiles and console. LLD, in Japan. Webtiles only. CXC, in France. Webtiles and console. CPO, in Australia. Webtiles and console. The full server list is available here, as well as instructions [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last year, a whole host of new servers have come online for play.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://kr.dobrazupa.org:8080/"><b>CKR</b></a>, in Korea. Webtiles only.</li>
<li><a href="http://crawl.berotato.org/"><b>CBRO</b></a>, in Georgia, USA. Webtiles and console.</li>
<li><a href="http://lazy-life.ddo.jp:8080/"><b>LLD</b></a>, in Japan. Webtiles only.</li>
<li><a href="http://crawl.xtahua.com/"><b>CXC</b></a>, in France. Webtiles and console.</li>
<li><a href="https://crawl.project357.org/"><b>CPO</b></a>, in Australia. Webtiles and console.</li>
</ul>
<p>The full server list is available <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/howto">here</a>, as well as instructions for getting started.</p>
<p>Many thanks to the people who have kindly volunteered to host these &#8211; and happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/new-servers/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 3 November 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-november-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-november-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 05:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=3000</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! Lots of refactoring this week, with the usual mess of bugs; not so many feature changes. That said, here&#8217;s the list: New monster: Caustic Shrikes, appearing in the nastiest parts of Depths. They come in packs, hit hard, resist fire and cold, and cover you with acid. Also, they&#8217;re twice as fast as [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! Lots of refactoring this week, with the usual mess of bugs; not so many feature changes. That said, here&#8217;s the list:</p>
<ul>
<li>New monster: Caustic Shrikes, appearing in the nastiest parts of Depths. They come in packs, hit hard, resist fire and cold, and cover you with acid. Also, they&#8217;re twice as fast as you. Caution is recommended.</li>
<li>New item: phantom mirrors, one-use evocables. When used, they create a temporary friendly clone of a targeted monster.</li>
<li>Irradiate now does somewhat more damage at low power, and somewhat less at high power. The malmutation effect (for enemies) is now guaranteed.</li>
<li>Rust devils do somewhat less damage, but their corrosion now triggers every time they hit.</li>
<li>Death scarabs now do considerably more damage.</li>
<li>Silver statues are now obsidian, instead. (This has no mechanical effects.)</li>
<li>Rings of slaying are now capped at +6, not +8 or +144.</li>
<li>Blessed Blades are, tragically, gone.</li>
<li>Card changes:
<ul>
<li>All decks can now be evoked from the inventory.</li>
<li>Nemelex&#8217;s Draw One and Peek at Two have drawn their last breaths.</li>
<li>The Metamorphosis card has magically transformed into nothing at all; it is no more.</li>
<li>Dowsing is no longer in the Deck of Battle.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mennas no longer mumbles.</li>
<li>Norris now follows the one true god, GOD_NAMELESS.</li>
<li>Prince Ribbit no longer turns back into a frog when raised from the dead.</li>
<li>Monsters casting Freeze now check their targets&#8217; cold resistance, rather than their own.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-november-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 27 October 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-october-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-october-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 04:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! It&#8217;s set to be a spooky week. Get ready for some fresh changes&#8230; and maybe drop by on the 31st, for a slightly different experience :) Clouds of draining now work like other sources of draining; they&#8217;re reduced by each pip of rN &#038; negated at rN+++, rather than being completely negated by [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers! It&#8217;s set to be a spooky week. Get ready for some fresh changes&#8230; and maybe drop by on the 31st, for a slightly different experience :)</p>
<ul>
<li>Clouds of draining now work like other sources of draining; they&#8217;re reduced by each pip of rN &#038; negated at rN+++, rather than being completely negated by a single pip of rN.</li>
<li>Clouds of miasma now apply the &#8216;rot&#8217; status, rather than causing rotting directly &#038; immediately.</li>
<li>New tomb monsters!
<ul>
<li>Ushabti, fearsome funerary statues, which breathe a heady mix of draining clouds &#038; miasma, and rumble resoundingly to alert enemies from a great distance.</li>
<li>Death scarabs, fast-moving swarming insects. They trail miasma and bite to drain life, speed, and skill, in addition to applying rN-.</li>
<li>Anubis guards, living foes that have been conditioned immunity to all forms of pain and torment. They breathe draining, dispel undead, confuse, and howl to reveal your location to other anubis guards.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chunk changes:
<ul>
<li>All chunks of an edibility type (clean, poisonous, mutagenic&#8230;) now merge together, into an undifferentiated meaty slurry. (Also, a single inventory stack.)</li>
<li>Rotten chunks are gone; chunks rot away directly.</li>
<li>Rotten corpses are likewise gone; corpses rot directly into skeletons.</li>
<li>Blood no longer coagulates, but rots away directly.</li>
<li>Ghouls now gain as much healing from clean chunks as they previously gained from rotten chunks. (There was surprisingly little difference.)</li>
<li>Ghouls now always heal rot when eating chunks. (There was a 75% per-chunk chance, before.)</li>
<li>Gods that forbade the player from eating certain types of creatures (that is, the good gods and Beogh) now forbid them from butchering those creatures, instead. Penalties are much steeper. (The old ones were surprisingly trivial!)</li>
<li>Effects that spectacularly disintegrate creatures (Orb of Destruction, Disintegrate, etc) do not create any chunks if eating those creatures is forbidden by your god.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Spell miscast effects have been <i>hugely</i> revamped. The summary is as long as the rest of this post, just&#8230; <a href="http://s-z.org/neil/git/?p=crawl.git;a=commit;h=caa8d4fddc532dc37178b87b0953628a8966c1ab">read the commit.</a> I&#8217;m sorry.</li>
<li>All short blades (except for the Captain&#8217;s Cutlass) now do piercing damage; this is relevant to short swords and cutlasses. The latter have been renamed to rapiers, being as they no longer cut.</li>
<li>Sense invisibility has been simplified; the range limit has been dropped, and monsters with it now have strict immunity to the &#8216;blind&#8217; effect (from dazzle, zin, ru), rather than being partially affected. A number of other niche special effects (e.g. better detection of sneaking characters) have also been dropped.</li>
<li>Xtahua&#8217;s breath now creates a cloud of flames, like red draconians&#8217;.</li>
<li>Tiamat can now be any colour of draconian, except grey.</li>
<li>Mnoleg&#8217;s tentacles, so briefly with us, have departed for another realm. Mnoleg now has Malign Gateway again, as well as a new set of excitingly branded melee attacks.</li>
<li>Ashenzari&#8217;s clear vision perk now also grants immunity to the negative effects of blurry vision mutations.</li>
<li>All food other than rations, chunks, and royal jellies now takes one turn to eat.</li>
<li>Corrosion is now displayed in the weapon bar as a temporary penalty to weapon enchantment; e.g., with one level of corrosion, a +1 mace would show up as -2 (and red).</li>
<li>Branch tiles have been widely adjusted; in particular, Spider has been recolored significantly.</li>
<li>A wide variety of missing &#8216;emergency&#8217; spell flags have been reinstated; liches should be significantly less likely to Banish players on sight.</li>
<li>Entering a piety-sacrifice trove while wearing an amulet of faith no longer causes the player to be excommunicated.</li>
<li>Hell beasts no longer slow down when hasted.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-october-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 20 October 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-20-october-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-20-october-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 01:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2982</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, crawlers! First, fair warning: a very large rewrite of monster spellcasting &#038; special abilities landed in trunk this morning. This lets us do some very cool things (some of which are already in!), but it&#8217;s also a large amount of new code, which is going to have a corresponding number of new bugs. For [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, crawlers!</p>
<p>First, fair warning: a very large rewrite of monster spellcasting &#038; special abilities landed in trunk this morning. This lets us do some very cool things (some of which are already in!), but it&#8217;s also a large amount of new code, which is going to have a corresponding number of new bugs. For the next day or two, trunk will be a little more unstable than usual.</p>
<p>One thing you can do to help, as always, is to report any bugs you find on <a href="https://crawl.develz.org/mantis/main_page.php">the official bugtracker</a>. We get notified whenever a new bug is filed, and while we can&#8217;t promise we&#8217;ll fix everything immediately, we do our best!</p>
<p>With all that said, let&#8217;s get to the week&#8217;s new features!</p>
<ul>
<li>Mennas can now occasionally be found wandering through Pandemonium. His Confusion &#8216;recitation&#8217; has been replaced with Mass Confusion.</li>
<li>The Great Lords of Pandemonium &#8211; that is, Cerebov, Lom Lobon, etc &#8211; will reappear on later floors of Pandemonium once their rune is stolen, unless and until the player kills them.</li>
<li>Lom Lobon (and, to a lesser extent, Gloorx Vloq) are much more likely to spend their time casting spells rather than attacking in melee.</li>
<li>Player ghosts and spellforged servitors can now know more than six spells.</li>
<li>New items:
<ul>
<li>Shadow dragon armour. 10 AC and 15 ER, the same as Storm Dragon Armour, but instead of rElec, shadow dragon armour gives Stlth++++. (The weight of the armour naturally subtracts exactly Stlth+++, leaving players wearing this armour at Stlth+ above what they would have with no armour at all.)</li>
<li>Quicksilver dragon armour. 10 AC, 6 ER, and MR+; however, it cannot be enchanted with scrolls of enchant armour, and is always +0.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Scale Mail now only has 10 ER, down from 11.</li>
<li>Dithmenos now specifically hates fire (owing to a <i>very</i> old divine grudge), rather than &#8216;fire and illuminating effects&#8217;. The glimmering light of a Corona will no longer bring down the dread wrath of Dithmenos upon worshippers.</li>
<li>A new malmutation: &#8220;MP-powered wands&#8221;, which increases the power of your wands, but makes them cost MP with every zap.</li>
<li>New tiles: Irradiate, Hydra Form, Octopode &#038; Felid Blade Hands (if that&#8217;s the right word?), triple swords, and more.</li>
<li>Various skill titles have been rearranged or replaced; notably, Cheibriados&#8217;s invocations titles have been completely rewritten from scratch.</li>
<li>Hydra Form, like most forms, now has a special message when praying at altars.</li>
<li>The legendary serpent Jrmungandr is now selectable by tiles players. (&#8220;tile_player_tile=tile:mons_jormungandr&#8221;.) Beware his ophidian wrath!</li>
<li>Wumpuses can occasionally be heard roaring in the distance.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-20-october-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.15.2 bugfix release</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-2-bugfix-release</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-2-bugfix-release#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 03:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2980</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers: We bring to you another bugfix release, featuring the following: Assorted crash fixes, bug fixes, and display cleanups. Always weight formicid weapon acquirement towards two-handed weapons. Allow in-game updates to the mon_glyph option to change the glyph. Allow the option syntax of mon_glyph = : in order to set the color/glyph of one [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers:</p>
<p>We bring to you another bugfix release, featuring the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Assorted crash fixes, bug fixes, and display cleanups.</li>
<li>Always weight formicid weapon acquirement towards two-handed weapons.</li>
<li>Allow in-game updates to the mon_glyph option to change the glyph.</li>
<li>Allow the option syntax of mon_glyph = <mon1>:<mon2> in order to set the color/glyph of one monster using the base values of another monster.</li>
<li>In tiles, the tile_player_tile option allows you to specify an arbitrary monster tile to display for your character. The options tile_weapon_offsets and tile_shield_offsets can be used to adjust the player weapon and shield location when using these custom tiles.</li>
<li>For use with tile_player_tile: the old orb guardian tile, a new monster vampire tile, and weapon/shield offsets for various monster tiles.</li>
</ul>
<p>Builds for most platforms are now available over at the <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">downloads page</a>.</p>
<p>Happy Crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-2-bugfix-release/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 13 October 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-october-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-october-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 04:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2973</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Fresh trunk changes, coming your way. Look out! New spell: Irradiate (L5 Conj/Tmut). Blasts adjacent foes with pure magical radiation, doing heavy damage and frequently malmutating the unfortunate victims. Also, contaminates the caster; 2-4 casts of the spell will put you into yellow (dangerous) contamination. Found in the Book of Transfigurations and the [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Fresh trunk changes, coming your way. Look out!</p>
<ul>
<li>New spell: Irradiate (L5 Conj/Tmut). Blasts adjacent foes with pure magical radiation, doing heavy damage and frequently malmutating the unfortunate victims. Also, contaminates the caster; 2-4 casts of the spell will put you into yellow (dangerous) contamination. Found in the Book of Transfigurations and the Book of Alchemy.</li>
<li>Monster malmutations are now temporary, but more significant. Good news for Beoghites&#8230;?</li>
<li>Ice Form has been moved from the Book of Transfigurations to the Book of Ice.</li>
<li>Ice, Dragon, Tree, and Fungus forms no longer meld octopode rings.</li>
<li>Instead of starting with a level 1 spell memorized, wanderers get a randart spellbook with a couple of low-level spells in it.</li>
<li>Wanderers can start with an elemental evoker or a box of beasts in place of a wand.</li>
<li>Jump attack (and the boots of jumping) are no more.</li>
<li>Magic immunity no longer confers confusion immunity to monsters.</li>
<li>Frederick has realized his true potential; he is now a Demigod. Grovel at his boots, pitiful god-havers!</li>
<li>Player ghosts now have their weapon brands displayed. Never again will you have to hunt down morgue files to check if that AK ghost has a distortion weapon!</li>
<li>Ghosts of characters that died while paralyzed no longer have 0 EV.</li>
<li>Corrosion resistance can now appear on randart armour.</li>
<li>Cloaks of darkness have been renamed to cloaks of invisibility.</li>
<li>Gold dragon armour has been reduced from 25 to 23 EVP, the same as crystal plate.</li>
<li>Unarmed combat delay penalties from armour have been substantially de-randomized; they&#8217;re now consistently around the average of the old values.</li>
<li>Monsters with drowning attacks (water nymphs, drowned souls, etc) can no longer kill players who are in Death&#8217;s Door. (However, falling into deep water still can.)</li>
<li>Chain Lightning can no longer arc out of LOS.</li>
<li>&#8216;Monster spells&#8217; (e.g. Ghostly Fireball) can now be displayed in the spell finder. (?/S)</li>
<li>New options for tiles players: tile_weapon_offsets and tile_shield_offsets, allowing players using custom tiles (with tile_player_tile) to precisely adjust the placement of their equipment.</li>
<li>New tiles for double and triple swords, among other things.</li>
<li>Players can no longer wear the Amulet of Vitality on their tentacles.</li>
<li>Major balance change: Abandon God is now available even when the player is silenced.</li>
<li>Octopode players are now properly informed when their tentacles begin to smoulder.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-october-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 8 October 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-october-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-october-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 15:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2967</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Ready to devour some fresh trunk changes? (Ha ha! It is a Hydra Form joke.) All joking aside &#8211; if you are not ready, please do not read the below. Thanks. New spell: Hydra Form. Attacks all adjacent enemies and devours the slain for nutrition and healing. Found in the Book of Transfigurations [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Ready to <i>devour</i> some fresh trunk changes? (Ha ha! It is a Hydra Form joke.) All joking aside &#8211; if you are not ready, please do not read the below. Thanks.</p>
<ul>
<li>New spell: Hydra Form. Attacks all adjacent enemies and devours the slain for nutrition and healing. Found in the Book of Transfigurations and a new book, the Fen Folio.</li>
<li>Monster AC, EV, and MR are now displayed as bars in their description. (When examined, or through ?/M.)</li>
<li>Wand changes:
<ul>
<li>Wand type (not charge count) is auto-ID&#8217;d on pickup.</li>
<li>Zapping wands that don&#8217;t have their charge charge count identifies wastes several charges.</li>
<li>Many weak wands have had their max charge count increased.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Claymores have been renamed to triple swords; bastard swords have been renamed to double swords. Mega excite.</li>
<li>Regeneration has been moved from rings to amulets; accordingly, the Ring of Vitality is now the Amulet of Vitality.</li>
<li>The Hat of the Alchemist is now -2 (rElec rPois rF rC rN MR rMut rCorr). Beware the AC cost&#8230;</li>
<li>Cleaving attacks (from axes and Hydra Form) try to hit all adjacent enemies, rather than being blocked by walls. (How many people reading this actually knew that axes cleaving could be blocked by walls&#8230;?)</li>
<li>Demigod tweaks: They now gain 2x stats every third level, rather than one stat on 2/3 levels. They also now have innate Sustain Abilities.</li>
<li>Iron devils have been upgraded to rust devils, which do less damage but corrode with their touch.</li>
<li>Derived undead (zombies, skeletons, &#038;c) now have their full names displayed. (E.g., &#8220;orc warrior zombie&#8221;.)</li>
<li>More potion tiles &#038; randart helmet &#038; robe tiles should now show up in-game.</li>
<li>Formicids can no longer move in treeform by tunneling through rock; nor, similarly, can they shaft themselves while in treeform.</li>
<li>It is no longer possible to receive the message &#8220;you meow your recitation at the orc.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-8-october-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 30 September 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-30-september-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-30-september-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2958</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! It&#8217;s been a while, but now that the tournament is over, the 0.16 season has kicked off with a bang. Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new so far in trunk! New god: Ru the Awakened, a new temple god, lord of sacrifice and power! Periodically offers the player a choice of three permanent sacrifices in exchange [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! It&#8217;s been a while, but now that the tournament is over, the 0.16 season has kicked off with a bang. Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new so far in trunk!</p>
<ul>
<li>New god: Ru the Awakened, a new temple god, lord of sacrifice and power!
<ul>
<li>Periodically offers the player a choice of three permanent sacrifices in exchange for piety. All abilities scale with piety; piety never decreases.</li>
<li>Leaving Ru incurs no wrath, but leaves all your sacrifices in place (permanently).</li>
<li>1*: Enemies may fail to attack you, or even attack each other or themselves instead.</li>
<li>2*: Enemies that hurt you may be punished with status effects.</li>
<li>3*: Draw Out Power: restore health and mana to yourself, break free of webs and constriction, and cure confusion and petrification. Inflicts minor self-drain and exhaustion.</li>
<li>4*: Power Leap: Blinks you three tiles and deals high AOE damage at your destination. Costs exhaustion.</li>
<li>5*: Apocalypse: Deals very high damage to all monsters in LOS and inflicts statuses. Costs heavy drain and exhaustion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Monster changes:
<ul>
<li>Mermaids have been renamed to sirens; sirens have been renamed to merfolk avatars.</li>
<li>Mimics now cackle and vanish (forever) when discovered. This optimizes their psychological damage potential (PDP).</li>
<li>The Serpent of Hell is considerably tougher; it now has three heads which can attack and/or breathe separately, and can also summon (dragon-shaped) backup.</li>
<li>Mnoleg now has a pair of tentacles, acting similarly to eldritch tentacles.</li>
<li>New monster: elemental wellsprings, appearing in Cocytus. They fire powerful waves of water which produce hostile water elementals &#8211; but deplete their own &#8216;health&#8217; in the process.</li>
<li>New monster: bennu, the divine phoenix, appearing in Tomb. Attacks with fire, draining, and holy; when killed, explodes into ghostly flame and instantly returns to life (once).</li>
<li>Curse skulls now move &#8211; fast!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Completing a ziggurat (by exiting from the top floor, zig:27) makes all subsequent zigs harder. Dare you face the terror of the Megazig?</li>
<li>Ziggurats now only require two runes to enter, instead of three.</li>
<li>A Hall of Blades area (not branch) is now guaranteed on Elf:2.</li>
<li>Demigods now gain one stat of their choice on 2/3 levels (2,3,5,6&#8230;26,27), instead of gaining one stat of their choice on every third level and one random stat on every other level.</li>
<li>All species can now choose &#8216;unarmed&#8217; when playing backgrounds that allow a weapon choice.</li>
<li>Necromutated characters can now memorize spells normally, even ones that undead characters are unable to cast.</li>
<li>Dragon Form now provides a spell power &#038; success chance enhancer for Dragon&#8217;s Call.</li>
<li>The captain&#8217;s cutlass is now +5 (was +10) and can disarm enemies.</li>
<li>TSO&#8217;s Divine Shield no longer benefits from Shields skill.</li>
<li>Zin&#8217;s Hell effect protection has been halved; it now caps out at a 50% chance to block the terrors of Hell at max piety, down from 100%.</li>
<li>Zin&#8217;s Recite is now more effective at very low Invocations.</li>
<li>A third page has been added to the god description (^) screen, listing causes and effects of divine wrath.</li>
<li>Some effects (Shatter, banishment, etc.) now display animations.</li>
<li>Stealth is now displayed as a bar in the % screen. (The old &#8216;stealth words&#8217;) are still visible with @.)</li>
<li>Monsters no longer appear on the minimap.</li>
<li>The init file now allows you to specify an arbitrary monster tile for your character to be displayed as. Play as the Royal Jelly you always knew you were!</li>
<li>Porcupine-shaped players now have blood.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-30-september-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>More fanart!</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/more-fanart</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/more-fanart#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 00:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dpeg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have had the luck to receive some great contributions lately, which I immediately added to the Crawl Art page. This time we get one very busy minotaur, an overlord and, a novelty, miniatures! As usual, if you made some Crawl fanart yourself, or know someone who did, then do not hesitate to contact me [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have had the luck to receive some great contributions lately, which I immediately added to the <a href="http://arts.crawl.develz.org/">Crawl Art page</a>. This time we get one very busy minotaur, an overlord and, a novelty, miniatures!</p>
<p>As usual, if you made some Crawl fanart yourself, or know someone who did, then do not hesitate to contact me (either by email or by tavern message).</p>
<p>Many thanks to all the contributors, and may your inspirations run free! </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/more-fanart/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.15 Tournament Results</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament-results</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament-results#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 17:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elliptic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2938</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 0.15 tournament is over. For 16 days, players could compete for tournament points and banners by playing 0.15 games on the public servers. For the second tournament in a row, the winning player was Tolias, with 7940 points. Over the course of the tournament Tolias won an record-breaking 26 games, many of them with [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.15/overview.html" title="0.15 tournament">0.15 tournament</a> is over. For 16 days, players could compete for tournament points and banners by playing 0.15 games on the public servers.</p>
<p>For the second tournament in a row, the winning player was <strong>Tolias</strong>, with 7940 points. Over the course of the tournament Tolias won an record-breaking 26 games, many of them with Nemelex&#8217;s Choice species/background combinations. In second place was <strong>Yermak</strong>, with 7156 points and 17 wins. Yermak received 17 of the 20 Tier III banners, more than any other player. In third place was <strong>johnnyzero</strong>, with 6975 points and 17 wins, including the second-longest streak in the tournament (7 games).</p>
<p>The fastest wins in the tournament were achieved by <strong>Bloax</strong> (turncount, 13320 turns with a VSTm of Cheibriados) and <strong>perunasaurus</strong> (realtime, 1h 11m with a MiBe). <strong>tlatlagkaus</strong> had the highest score, 42M points with a VSBe. <strong>ebarrett</strong> had the longest streak, of 10 games. <strong>Snack</strong> was the only player to attain Tier III of Lugonu&#8217;s banner, The Heretic. Both the first victory of the tournament and the victory in the tournament with the latest start were claimed by <strong>perunasaurus</strong>.</p>
<p>The clan competition was won by <strong>knock knock knocking on holy pans door</strong> (28664 points). <strong>HuAs Priest</strong> (27291 points) and <strong>AWBW &#8211; SpannLords</strong> (18656 points) were second and third respectively. There were 127 clans in all.</p>
<p>The tournament ended with one more record: 106 wins on a single day! (Note that <a href="http://crawl.akrasiac.org/scoring/per-day.html">this page</a> only lists 100 wins due to time zones.) Here are some assorted statistics on the tournament games (with quits removed), compared with the 0.14 tournament (in parentheses):</p>
<pre>
Players with at least one game: 2326 (2318)
Players with at least one game to reach XL 9: 1527 (1589)
Players who got a rune: 743 (787)
Players who won a game: 370 (325)
Total wins: 992 (743)
Win %: 1.71% (1.31%)
Total player time: 33903 hrs (35858 hrs)
Avg player time: 14.6 hrs (15.5 hrs)
Proportion of players using webtiles: 85.1% (80.4%)
Proportion of winners using webtiles: 76.0% (70.6%)
</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament-results/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.15.1 bugfix release</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-1-bugfix-release</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-1-bugfix-release#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 23:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2933</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers: With the tournament now over comes another long-standing Crawl tradition &#8211; the release afterwards containing all of the bugs found and fixed during the tournament, 0.15.1: Assorted crash fixes. Monsters don&#8217;t benefit from player throwing skill. Monsters no longer flee at random on re-entering a level after a short time. Several messages correctly [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers:</p>
<p>With the tournament now over comes another long-standing Crawl tradition &#8211; the release afterwards containing all of the bugs found and fixed during the tournament, 0.15.1:</p>
<ul>
<li>Assorted crash fixes.</li>
<li>Monsters don&#8217;t benefit from player throwing skill.</li>
<li>Monsters no longer flee at random on re-entering a level after a short time.</li>
<li>Several messages correctly no longer appear for out-of-sight monster actions.</li>
<li>Dithmenos&#8217; stealth bonus works properly again.</li>
<li>Several spell icons that missed the initial 0.15 release.</li>
</ul>
<p>Builds for most platforms are now available over at the <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">downloads page</a>.</p>
<p>Happy Crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-1-bugfix-release/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crawl 0.15: &#8220;Storm Over Zot&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-storm-over-zot</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-storm-over-zot#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 04:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2914</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are proud to announce the release of Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup 0.15: &#8220;Storm Over Zot&#8221;! 0.15 features a new deity and many, many tweaks to and streamlining of the general flow of gameplay. Download DCSS 0.15 here, or play it online on one of many servers across the world! The release tournament will begin [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to announce the release of Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup 0.15: &#8220;Storm Over Zot&#8221;! 0.15 features a new deity and many, many tweaks to and streamlining of the general flow of gameplay.</p>
<p>Download DCSS 0.15 <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">here</a>, or <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/howto">play it online</a> on one of many servers across the world!</p>
<p>The release tournament will begin at 20:00 UTC on Friday 29 August, with all online 0.15 games counting towards your score. See the <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.15/">tournament website</a>for more details, including how to set up or join a clan.</p>
<p>0.15&#8242;s highlights include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Characters:</strong> Characters are now unencumbered by carrying-weight limits.</li>
<li><strong>Combat:</strong> The system of ranged combat has been fundamentally redesigned: it now behaves more like melee combat in terms of accuracy and damage, and is generally more consistent.</li>
<li><strong>Gods:</strong> Qazlal Stormbringer makes a thunderous debut, bringing elemental destruction to those unfortunate enough to cross paths with worshippers. Nemelex Xobeh&#8217;s decks have been shuffled considerably and are granted on exploration rather than through sacrifice of items.</li>
<li><strong>Items:</strong> Items are no longer subject to destruction through fire or cold, and equipment corrosion is more severe but temporary.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a list of other major changes, see the <a href="https://gitorious.org/crawl/crawl/blobs/stone_soup-0.15/crawl-ref/docs/changelog.txt">changelog</a>. Many thanks to all those who have <a href="https://gitorious.org/crawl/crawl/blobs/stone_soup-0.15/crawl-ref/CREDITS.txt">contributed</a>to Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup. We hope you enjoy playing 0.15!</p>
<p>
<strong>Update 2014-08-30</strong>: OS X builds are now avaialable from the <a href="downloads/">downloads</a> page <cite><a href="author/neil">neil</a></cite></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-storm-over-zot/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.15 Tournament</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 02:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2906</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 0.15 tournament will begin in just one week! From 20:00 UTC Friday 29 August through 20:00 UTC Sunday 14 September, any 0.15 game played on any of the online servers will count for the tournament. 0.15 will be officially released before the start of the tournament &#8211; at the moment, a 0.15 beta is [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 0.15 tournament will begin in just one week! From <strong>20:00 UTC Friday 29 August</strong> through <strong>20:00 UTC Sunday 14 September</strong>, any <strong>0.15 game</strong> played on any of the online servers will count for the tournament. 0.15 will be officially released before the start of the tournament &#8211; at the moment, a 0.15 beta is playable on all the online servers <del>except CDO</del>.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.15/">rules page</a> contains all the details about how to score points and earn banners in the tournament. Only a few changes to the banners this tournament.</p>
<p>As usual, clans (teams of up to six players) can be formed and changed until one week into the tournament, so don&#8217;t panic if you aren&#8217;t on one yet! (Being on a clan isn&#8217;t necessary to participate in the tournament, but it can be a lot of fun.)</p>
<p>Once the tournament has started, the <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.15/overview.html">tournament leaderboard</a> will contain the current results. (Before tournament start, some scores might briefly appear on this page as we test the tournament scripts, but they are just for testing.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-15-tournament/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 11 August 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-august-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-august-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 04:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2897</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! This week, I&#8217;ll write up the latest changes to trunk and 0.15. It&#8217;s pretty quiet, since there&#8217;s a feature freeze in preparation for 0.15&#8242;s release, but we still have a few things. Ugly things have gotten&#8230; a bit uglier. ( _) ( _)>- (_) Ugly things now have the stats (hp, damage, etc) [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! This week, I&#8217;ll write up the latest changes to trunk and 0.15. It&#8217;s pretty quiet, since there&#8217;s a feature freeze in preparation for 0.15&#8242;s release, but we still have a few things.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ugly things have gotten&#8230; a bit uglier. ( _)    ( _)>-    (_) Ugly things now have the stats (hp, damage, etc) that very ugly things used to have; very ugly things have been upgraded to be, well, a bit like miniature elemental dire elephants. To compensate, ugly things no longer spawn in bands before D:13.</li>
<li>Potions of resistance now grant acid/corrosion resistance.</li>
<li>A number of enemies have been upgraded (sidegraded?) with a new &#8216;corrosive bolt&#8217; spell; Deep Elf Sorcerers, Tengu Reavers, and Liches.</li>
<li>A great number of new tiles have been added:</li>
<ul>
<li>All projectiles have been reworked to be more distinctive from melee weapons.</li>
<li>Hand crossbows have a new set of sprites, replacing some decade-old placeholder programming art.</li>
<li>Robes have a large set of new, varied sprites.</li>
<li>Various enemies have had their sprites upgraded; Frances, thrashing horrors, and torpor snails.</li>
<li>Nemelex invocation icons have been upgraded to the new style.</li>
<li>Various miscellaneous spells have new icons.</li>
</ul>
<li>Mutagenic clouds now give nontrivial levels of glow; they&#8217;ll now cause yellow contam within 2-4 turns, from the previous minimum of 5 turns and average of 9.</li>
<li>The Spectral Weapon description (for both spell &#038; item) now actually mentions the injury bond effect.</li>
<li>Ranged weapons have been slightly tweaked; shortbows &#038; hand crossbows are very slightly stronger, triple crossbows are very slightly weaker.</li>
<li>?/S no longer provides advice on warding off the evil eye.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-11-august-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crawl 0.15 beta</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-beta</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-beta#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 04:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Crawl 0.15 has entered the beta phase; it is now playable on CBRO, CSZO, and CAO, and should be available on other servers soon. Local beta binaries should also be available in the immediate future. See also the 0.15 changelog. The tournament will be announced&#8230; soon!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers!</p>
<p>Crawl 0.15 has entered the beta phase; it is now playable on <a href="http://crawl.berotato.org:8080/#lobby">CBRO</a>, <a href="http://crawl.s-z.org">CSZO</a>, and <a href="http://crawl.akrasiac.org:8080">CAO</a>, and should be available on other servers soon. Local beta binaries should also be available in the immediate future.</p>
<p>See also the <a href="http://s-z.org/neil/git/?p=crawl.git;a=blob;f=crawl-ref/docs/changelog.txt;hb=refs/heads/stone_soup-0.15">0.15 changelog</a>.</p>
<p>The tournament will be announced&#8230; soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-15-beta/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 28 July 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-28-july-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-28-july-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 05:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! This week, I&#8217;ll write up the latest changes to trunk, plus one fact about world geography. Spells that previously operated on spell skill directly have been changed to use spellpower. This affects Death&#8217;s Door, Passwall, Sticks to Snakes, Condensation Shield, Ozocubu&#8217;s Armour, Stoneskin, Ice Form, and Statue Form. Shatter now always affects the [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! This week, I&#8217;ll write up the latest changes to trunk, plus one fact about world geography.</p>
<ul>
<li>Spells that previously operated on spell skill directly have been changed to use spellpower. This affects Death&#8217;s Door, Passwall, Sticks to Snakes, Condensation Shield, Ozocubu&#8217;s Armour, Stoneskin, Ice Form, and Statue Form.</li>
<li>Shatter now always affects the full LOS, rather than sometimes affecting a smaller radius at low Earth Magic skill.</li>
<li>Statue Form no longer gives -10 EV.</li>
<li>Sublimation of Blood now <b>actually</b> only draws from the caster&#8217;s body, rather than using chunks. Really, this time.</li>
<li>rPois now gives a consistent 66% resistance against poison effects. This includes &#8216;being poisoned&#8217; (down from 90%), &#8216;being hit with curare&#8217; (down from 80%), and &#8216;direct poison damage&#8217; (up from 50%). &#8220;Strong poison&#8221; (from e.g. redbacks) is now affected by rPois normally, instead of automatically piercing it at half strength. Wasp poison can also now partially pierce rPois, with a chance to cause slowing when it would have otherwise caused paralysis.</li>
<li>rCorr now gives only 50% resistance against the corrosion status effect, instead of 90%.</li>
<li>The Mace of Brilliance has become a star &#8211; specifically, the +1 Eveningstar &#8220;Brilliance&#8221;.</li>
<li>To drive from Tripoli, Libya to Kano, Nigeria, would require traveling roughly the same distance as a trip from Barcelona, Spain to Moscow, Russia.</li>
<li>Torpor Snail slow now ends as soon as they die or break LOS. Their frequency has been reduced considerably in Lair &#038; Spider (now that they&#8217;ve had some good testing), and they&#8217;ve been moved in small numbers to a few other places.</li>
<li>Spriggan air mages no longer cast Haste.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-28-july-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 21 July 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-21-july-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-21-july-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 06:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2883</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Another week, another set of crawl changes. Draining no longer permanently reduces monsters&#8217; stats (&#8220;hit dice&#8221;); instead, it now applies a temporary &#8220;drained&#8221; status, which reduces their hit dice while in effect for most purposes. This means, among other things, that draining attacks will no longer reduce the XP you get for killing [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Another week, another set of crawl changes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Draining no longer permanently reduces monsters&#8217; stats (&#8220;hit dice&#8221;); instead, it now applies a temporary &#8220;drained&#8221; status, which reduces their hit dice while in effect for most purposes. This means, among other things, that draining attacks will no longer reduce the XP you get for killing monsters even slightly.</li>
<li>Draining weapons now trigger slightly less often, but will always apply &#8220;drained&#8221; to monsters when they do. (The old effect only activated for 20% of &#8220;draining&#8221; hits.)</li>
<li>A few more ranged weapon tweaks, tidying up after last week. Sling bullet &#038; crossbow damage slightly down; longbow base delay, also slightly down.</li>
<li>Similarly, deep elf master archers &#038; centaur warriors are now slightly stronger (to adjust for their weapons being weakened), and Joseph is slightly weakened (similarly).</li>
<li>Various sprites added; ghost crabs, triple crossbows &#038; hand crossbows (the latter being a placeholder). Greatslings sprite still pending, possibly because everyone&#8217;s arguing over the name.</li>
<li>Sprite revamps: in addition to the continuing work on ability &#038; spell icons, there are new sprites for the Hellfire effect (purple, to make it clearer that it&#8217;s Not Actually Fire), Shadow Demons, and the demon blade Leech.</li>
<li>New tiles option: tile_show_player_species, to display the player using the monster tile for their race instead of the normal sprite. (Note that this won&#8217;t display any equipment other the weapon &#038; shield you&#8217;re using, and not even that for a few races.)</li>
<li>Dispelling effects (the potion of cancellation, purple draconian/quicksilver dragon breath&#8230;) now reduces transformation durations to one turn instead of cancelling them instantly, to reduce instant deaths.</li>
<li>New Gozag wrath effect: a 1/5 chance of potion drinking to simply fail.</li>
<li>Donning &#038; doffing armour now always takes 5 turns.</li>
<li>Grey draconians have lost their former &#8220;trample monsters that are in a water tile while standing in deep water after successfully hitting with a tail-slap&#8221; ability.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-21-july-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 13 July 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-july-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-july-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 18:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2878</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Things have been pretty quiet until the last few days; lots of behind-the-scenes work, not much exciting to report. That&#8217;s happily over now, though, so here&#8217;s the latest changes in trunk! Big ranged weapon changes! The second half of the Great Ranged-Combat Rebalance: Slings have been split into two types: hunting slings, which [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Things have been pretty quiet until the last few days; lots of behind-the-scenes work, not much exciting to report. That&#8217;s happily over now, though, so here&#8217;s the latest changes in trunk!</p>
<ul>
<li>Big ranged weapon changes! The second half of the Great Ranged-Combat Rebalance:</li>
<ul>
<li>Slings have been split into two types: hunting slings, which replace the old basic sling type, and a new rare &#8216;greatsling&#8217; type. Both have had their damage increased considerably.</li>
<li>Crossbows have also been split up into multiple weapons. The hand crossbow returns as a starting weapon for crossbow hunters; &#8220;crossbows&#8221; have been renamed to arbalests, and adjusted to fill a mid/late-game role. There are rumors of a third, rare &#038; powerful crossbow type&#8230; </li>
<li>Bows have had their delay increased somewhat; shortbows now have slightly lower base damage, longbows somewhat higher.</li>
<li>Various unrands have been adjusted as appropriate. Punk is now a +7 greatsling; Hellfire is now an arbalest; Sniper is a &#8220;heavy crossbow&#8221;, with a base delay of 27.
</ul>
<li>Scrolls of vulnerability have been split in half. Status effect removal has been moved onto a new item type, &#8220;potions of cancellation&#8221;, which replace potions of paralysis. Scrolls of vulnerability now only have the &#8220;halve magic resistance on all visible creatures&#8221; effect.</li>
<li>Mimics are now somewhat more polite; they will no longer mimic doors, statues, fountains, or hatches.</li>
<li>The hoof mutation no longer gives extra damage or a stealth penalty when covered by boots.</li>
<li>Ashenzari now considers Felids fully bound when all three jewellery slots are cursed.</li>
<li>Undead monsters will now fall to pieces in deep water, instead of hiding invisibly.</li>
<li>Big fish, sharks, and lava worms have swum off to the great aquarium in the sky.</li>
<li>Potions of strong poison have taken the poison pill; they are no more.</li>
<li>Flying creatures no longer have a 2/3 chance to dodge throwing nets.</li>
<li>Brown (contaminated) chunks are gone, replaced with normal chunks.</li>
<li>Qazlal no longer provides a permanent resistance gift at 6* piety.</li>
<li>Pigs now have trotters.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-13-july-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 26 June 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-26-june-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-26-june-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2858</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Sorry for the downtime earlier this week; the database died, and then the backup database died while attempting to restore the primary. Thankfully, our admin was able to recover almost everything. So here&#8217;s a fresh pile of changes, seized from the heart of a dying sun! Beogh gifting has been somewhat revised: Beogh [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Sorry for the downtime earlier this week; the database died, and then the backup database died while attempting to restore the primary. Thankfully, our admin was able to recover almost everything. So here&#8217;s a fresh pile of changes, seized from the heart of a dying sun!</p>
<ul>
<li>Beogh gifting has been somewhat revised:
<ul>
<li>Beogh will now improve allies&#8217; equipment, enchanting them and improving their base type. (The latter would sometimes occur before, but very rarely.)</li>
<li>And he&#8217;ll gift weapons, armour, shields, and ammo to orcs who lack them.</li>
<li>And he&#8217;ll bless weapons and armour that the player has gifted.</li>
<li>And he&#8217;ll give some extra ammo to any orc that the player chooses to gift a ranged weapon to.</li>
<li>And orcs won&#8217;t drop their melee weapons when the player gives them a ranged weapon, or vice versa.</li>
</ul>
<li>The Trident of the Octopus King now gets an additional +1 for each Ring of the Octopus King its wielder wears, up to a maximum of +16. (But good luck getting that!)</li>
<li>Godless hill orcs can now convert to Beogh with &#8216;p&#8217; when orc priests are nearby, as an alternative to using the option from the abilities menu.</li>
<li>The Deck of Wonders is back to giving mainly strategic effects (e.g. Helix, Mercenary, etc), rather than duplicating the Deck of Battle.</li>
<li>New monster: torpor snails, found in Lair and Spider. Their enemies are slowed on sight, somewhat like ancient zymes.</li>
<li>Weapons and armour which aren&#8217;t visibly enchanted no longer have enchantments higher than +0.</li>
<li>The Staff of Air now activates its extra melee damage as often as other elemental staves.</li>
<li>Brown oozes and pulsating lumps have oozed off to the great slime pit in the sky.</li>
<li>The dragonslaying brand has been slain. (Except for Wyrmbane, of course.)</li>
<li>Scrolls of Enchant Weapon are now rarer, and always succeed on use.</li>
<li>Most randomly-placed teleport traps now disappear after one use.</li>
<li>Lost souls now make enemies into ghosts instead of specters.</li>
<li>Skullcrusher now gives +7 STR.</li>
</ul>
<p>0.15 will be released in mid-August.</p>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-26-june-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 15 June 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-june-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-june-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 19:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2849</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! A whole pile of changes, just waiting for some enterprising adventurer to seize them: Weapon enchantments and slaying bonuses (from artefacts and rings of slaying) have been merged into one number, which gives both +accuracy and +damage. Enchant Weapon scrolls have likewise been merged into a single type. Various unrands have been adjusted [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! A whole pile of changes, just waiting for some enterprising adventurer to seize them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Weapon enchantments and slaying bonuses (from artefacts and rings of slaying) have been merged into one number, which gives both +accuracy and +damage. Enchant Weapon scrolls have likewise been merged into a single type. Various unrands have been adjusted to account for this.</li>
<li>Monster item pickup:</li>
<ul>
<li>Monsters will no longer pick up items that players have seen.</li>
<li>Friendly monsters will no longer pick up any items at all. (And, accordingly, the old ctrl-t functionality has been removed.)</li>
<li>Beogh has a new ***** piety ability, allowing the player to gift items directly to named followers.</li>
<li>Beogh now improves allies&#8217; equipment by blessing them.</li>
<li>Mercenaries now start with slightly better items.</li>
</ul>
<li>Ctrl-T now toggles displaying enemies&#8217; weapons&#8217; glyphs while playing console.</li>
<li>Cross-training now gives a direct bonus to skills, rather than providing an aptitude bonus.</li>
<li>Anti-training has been removed.</li>
<li>New monster: Ghost crabs, appearing in the Crypt and Tartarus. The clouds of ghostly flame they breathe summon dangerous specters into fleeting existence.</li>
<li>Giant fireflies have flickered out of existence; spriggan riders now buzz into battle on deadly wasp mounts.</li>
<li>Halfling and kobold stats have been tweaked; halflings now have more str and less int/dex, and kobolds now have slightly more dex and slightly less str.</li>
<li>TSO no longer blasts you with cleansing fire when you kill holy monsters.</li>
<li>Simulacrum now works on a single corpse at the caster&#8217;s feet, creating several simulacrula from it. Monsters instead have an animate-dead like version that works on all corpses in LOS and produces half as many simulacrula.</li>
<li>Sublimation of Blood no longer uses chunks; it now only draws from the caster&#8217;s HP.</li>
<li>Temporary brand spells (Excruciating Wounds and Warp Weapon) can now be used on branded non-artefact weapons to temporarily re-brand them.</li>
<li>The Sack of Spiders now places webs directly onto enemies, rather than spreading them randomly around the area.</li>
<li>The Frost card has been removed, and replaced with Hammer; Flame has been renamed to Cloud, and now produces either fire or freezing clouds.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-15-june-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 7 June 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-june-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-june-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 17:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PleasingFungus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2841</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Fresh changes, right from the spriggan&#8217;s oven: Shields have been rebalanced: The effects of SH have been doubled; each point of SH now gives twice as much block chance as previously, making it very roughly equivalent to EV point-for-point. All sources of SH have been halved, except for shield enchantments. Large shields can [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Fresh changes, right from the spriggan&#8217;s oven:</p>
<ul>
<li>Shields have been rebalanced:</li>
<ul>
<li>The effects of SH have been doubled; each point of SH now gives twice as much block chance as previously, making it very roughly equivalent to EV point-for-point.</li>
<li>All sources of SH have been halved, except for shield enchantments.</li>
<li>Large shields can now be enchanted up to +8; normal &#8216;shields&#8217; can be enchanted up to +5. (Bucklers still cap at +3.)</li>
<li>Unrand shields have been tweaked. The Large Shield of Ignorance is now +6 (a small buff); the Shield of the Gong is now +18 (a larger buff); the Shield of Resistance is now +2 (a small nerf).</li>
</ul>
<li>Uniques are now announced by title when first appearing onscreen. Beware: Sigmund the Dreaded awaits!</li>
<li>Darts have darted away forever. Warpers now start with tomahawks of dispersal instead.</li>
<li>Confusing Touch has had its duration increased (though multiple casts no longer stack), and causes your attacks to do no damage while it&#8217;s in effect. Once it successfully confuses an enemy, the duration ends. It&#8217;s now level 2.</li>
<li>Giant Slugs and Elephant Slugs have gone to the great vegetable garden in the sky. Gastronok survives, now the last member of his species. His eyestalks quiver in a fashion both noble and tragic.</li>
<li>Curse Skulls have returned to their natural, immobile state.</li>
<li>The amulet of conservation and cloak of preservation are gone, now that item destruction is no more.</li>
<li>Maxwell&#8217;s Patent Armour now gives rF+ rC+ instead of conservation.</li>
<li>Acquirement no longer avoids giving you items you&#8217;re currently carrying (e.g. lamps of fire, etc)</li>
<li>Iron Trolls no longer appear outside Dis. (But watch this space!)</li>
<li>Spellforged Servitors will no longer turn on the player when damaged by their own conjured ball lightning. Or ever.</li>
<li>You can now cast Inner Flame on allies without angering them.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-june-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 29 May 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-29-may-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-29-may-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 09:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>reaverb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2828</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! There&#8217;s been enough changes this week for a slightly early update: The new_nemelex branch has landed: Nemelex Nemelex only gives piety for exploration rather than item sacrifices ordeck usage. Peek at Two now reveals the top cards of a deck but cannot be used withother Nemelex abilities Nemelex now only gifts decks of [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! There&#8217;s been enough changes this week for a slightly early update:</p>
<ul>
<li>The new_nemelex branch has landed:</li>
<ul>
<li>Nemelex</li>
<ul>
<li>Nemelex only gives piety for exploration rather than item sacrifices ordeck usage.</li>
<li>Peek at Two now reveals the top cards of a deck but cannot be used withother Nemelex abilities</li>
<li>Nemelex now only gifts decks of war and escape.</li>
</ul>
<li>Cards</li>
<ul>
<li>New cards</li>
<ul>
<li>Fortitude, which gives Damage Shaving and a bonus to strength.</li>
<li>Storm, which can make shallow water, a tornado, or cause swiftness.</li>
<li>Degeneration, which polymorphs nearby monsters into weaker ones.</li>
<li>Shaft, which creates a shaft under the player. This is an old effect of the Flight card.</li>
<li>Illusion, which summons an illusion of the player.</li>
</ul>
<li>Revamped cards</li>
<ul>
<li>Flame card now spawns flame clouds around the user and on hostiles ratherthan dealing damage.</li>
<li>Velocity card now hastes the slow and slows hasty rather than simplyspeeding up the player.</li>
</ul>
<li>Warp, Portal, Hammer, Spark, Flight, and Genie cards have been removed</li>
</ul>
<li>Decks of War now contain the Dowsing and Potion cards</li>
</ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 13px;">The chance of corroding equipment no longer considers item enchantment</span></li>
<li>I<span style="font-size: 13px;">tem destruction of scrolls and potions has been completely removed.</span></li>
<ul>
<li>Demonspawn facets which gave potion/scroll item conservation now give freezing/firecloud immunity earlier and separately.</li>
</ul>
<li>Halflings have rebalanced aptitudes, shifting them towards defense.</li>
<li>Kobolds no longer have disease resistance.</li>
<li>Tukima&#8217;s Dance now animates weapons held by monsters. The weapons will fight against their former owners. It is also now level 3.</li>
<li>Spider Form now moves at normal speed.</li>
<li>Some ability icons have new tiles.</li>
<li>All types of fruit have been merged together into one item type.</li>
<li>Cheese and sausages are no more.</li>
<li>New unrand: the +6 Majin-Bo {vamp, Archmagi, MP+6 Int+6}. A quarterstaffthat takes HP every time you cast a spell.</li>
<li>The dagger of Chilly Death now sometimes flash-freezes enemies, slowing theirmovement.</li>
<li>The scimitar of Flaming Death now sometimes applies sticky flame to its victims.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-29-may-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 23 May 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-may-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-may-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 15:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2821</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s your roughly weekly dose of trunk update news: The special diets of centaurs (fast metabolism 1, herbivorous 1) and halflings (slow metabolism 1) have been removed. Vampires always get the full effect of all potions, can always mutate, and always get the full effect of all mutations. Corrosion affects all of your [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s your roughly weekly dose of trunk update news:</p>
<ul>
<li>The special diets of centaurs (fast metabolism 1, herbivorous 1) and halflings (slow metabolism 1) have been removed.</li>
<li>Vampires always get the full effect of all potions, can always mutate, and always get the full effect of all mutations.</li>
<li>Corrosion affects all of your equipment, but only temporarily.</li>
<li>Purple (very) ugly things deal extra damage in lieu of a sickness attack.</li>
<li>Sustain abilities effects no longer stack.</li>
<li>Scrolls of brand weapon can roll any brand on an unbranded weapon.</li>
<li>Ambrosia and royal jellies have been removed; honeycombs have been renamed to royal jellies.</li>
<li>The Mercenary card generates base demonspawn instead of spriggan riders.</li>
<li>Sif Muna wrath can no longer cause amnesia.</li>
<li>Gods that give missile gifts can do so sooner, i.e. there is no skill-related breakpoint associated with it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-23-may-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 14 May 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-14-may-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-14-may-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2716</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new in trunk: The Lava Orc species has been removed. Player clinging (seen only in Spider Form and with the boots of the Spider) is no more. Kobolds, hill orcs, and ogres are no longer saprovorous. Ogres no longer have a fast metabolism. Silver statues and orange crystal statues are immune [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new in trunk:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Lava Orc species has been removed.</li>
<li>Player clinging (seen only in Spider Form and with the boots of the Spider) is no more.</li>
<li>Kobolds, hill orcs, and ogres are no longer saprovorous.</li>
<li>Ogres no longer have a fast metabolism.</li>
<li>Silver statues and orange crystal statues are immune to disintegration, but have less health and AC and have their abilities converted to spells such that they spam less; this implies OCS confusion can be resisted.</li>
<li>Bog bodies no longer randomly rot.</li>
<li>Removed monsters: shedu, plague shamblers.</li>
<li>New unrand: the +8 orange crystal plate armour {Archmagi, Int+3 Clar SustAb}</li>
<li>Potions of blood cure a point of ghoul rotting.</li>
<li>Removed unrands: the boots of the Spider.</li>
<li>Decks of wonders now contain Dowsing, Battlelust, Helm, and Shadow instead of Experience, Helix, Sage, and Trowel.</li>
<li>Decks of dungeon are no more.</li>
<li>The Potion card has a new list of effects: power 0 is decay/curing/agility/ might/brilliance; 1 has a chance of resistance/haste; 2 has a chance of magic/heal wounds.</li>
<li>Removed cards: Experience, Sage, Water, Vitrification, Trowel, Minefield, and Shuffle.</li>
<li>Zin&#8217;s Recite no longer prompts for a book, instead affecting all monsters in sight with the strongest effects that would impact them.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-14-may-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interim Win32 trunk builds</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/interim-win32-trunk-builds</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/interim-win32-trunk-builds#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 16:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2707</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! While we figure out how to get our server&#8217;s trunk build system up and running again, I&#8217;m going to provide occasional trunk builds for those clamouring for them. Enjoy! EDIT: We&#8217;ve reached a solution to get our trunk build system ready to serve builds again. EDIT: Greatzebu&#8217;s OSX build bot died but he [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! While we figure out how to get our server&#8217;s trunk build system up and running again, I&#8217;m going to provide <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/crawl-ref/files/Stone%20Soup/Trunk/">occasional trunk builds</a> for those clamouring for them.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>EDIT: <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/trunk">We&#8217;ve reached a solution to get our trunk build system ready to serve builds again</a>.</em></p>
<p><em>EDIT: <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/trunk/">Greatzebu&#8217;s OSX build bot died but he managed to get an OSX Tiles build up, too!</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/interim-win32-trunk-builds/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 7 May 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-may-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-may-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 01:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2701</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s the latest and greatest from trunk: The gods branch has landed, bringing two new gods: Gozag Ym Sagoz the Greedy and Qazlal Stormbringer. Both are temple gods with an altar either in Temple or on D:2-9. Gozag Charges a service fee for joining, dependent on the amount of gold that has been [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s the latest and greatest from trunk:</p>
<ul>
<li>The gods branch has landed, bringing two new gods: Gozag Ym Sagoz the Greedy and Qazlal Stormbringer. Both are temple gods with an altar either in Temple or on D:2-9.
<ul>
<li>Gozag
<ul>
<li>Charges a service fee for joining, dependent on the amount of gold that has been generated in the game.</li>
<li>Does not have piety.</li>
<li>Defeated enemies turn to gold; these gold piles distract nearby creatures, causing them to sometimes not act.</li>
<li>Potion Petition: purchase one set of potion effects.</li>
<li>Call Merchant: fund a merchant to set up shop somewhere near to areas of the dungeon you have explored.</li>
<li>Bribe Branch: send money to the inhabitants of a branch to turn them +      temporarily neutral or incite them to join you.</li>
<li>Duplication: one non-artefact item can be duplicated at an altar.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Qazlal
<ul>
<li>Piety on kills.</li>
<li>All followers are immune from their own clouds.</li>
<li>1*: Storm Shield: you passively generate elemental clouds around you and gain bonus SH, and gain RMsl at 3*; you also generate a lot of noise.</li>
<li>2*: Upheaval: blast a small nearby area with elemental forces.</li>
<li>3*: Elemental Force: turn nearby clouds into elementals.</li>
<li>4*: Elemental Adaptation: taking elemental or physical damage sometimes temporarily grants you resistance against that element.</li>
<li>5*: Disaster Area: blast the entire area around you with elemental forces.</li>
<li>6*: at an altar, gain a permanent elemental resistance of your choice for as long as you worship Qazlal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The Abyss no longer sometimes blocks blinking.</li>
<li>Wanderers have tweaked starting kits with generally better items.</li>
<li>Teleportitis cannot be controlled.</li>
<li>Manticores have an unlimited number of spike volleys.</li>
<li>Base draconians can become nonbase draconians with experience.</li>
<li>Undead and nonliving enemies regenerate as fast as other enemies.</li>
<li>Ghouls and necrophages can no longer equip weapons or armour.</li>
<li>Monster melee attacks can no longer destroy items.</li>
<li>Death Channel lasts twice as long.</li>
<li>The blowgun of the Assassin returns; it has a chance to affect the target more than normal blowguns.</li>
<li>Gloves of archery no longer penalise melee.</li>
<li>(Plain) bows have been renamed to shortbows.</li>
<li>Identify scrolls now always identify a single item.</li>
<li>Monsters with special attack flavours have this noted in their descriptions.</li>
<li>Summon Elemental has been removed.</li>
<li>Spriggan enchanters (the monster) and phoenixes have been removed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-7-may-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 3 May 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-may-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-may-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 01:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2699</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new in trunk: The ranged_combat branch has landed &#8211; it is a rewrite of the ranged combat system to be based on many of the same formulas as melee attacks, so the effect of AC/EV on ranged attacks is more predictable, weapon delay is more predictable, and even Throwing should be [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new in trunk:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <code>ranged_combat</code> branch has landed &#8211; it is a rewrite of the ranged combat system to be based on many of the same formulas as melee attacks, so the effect of AC/EV on ranged attacks is more predictable, weapon delay is more predictable, and even Throwing should be a viable option compared to the other ranged weapons.</li>
<li>Jewellery automatically identifies on equipping it.</li>
<li>Cleaving hits the full eight squares around a player.</li>
<li>Rebranding a distortion weapon no longer causes a distortion effect.</li>
<li>Scrolls of brand weapon can no longer affix brands; they keep their effect of rerolling a weapon brand.</li>
<li>Blessed weapons can be rebranded.</li>
<li>Amulets of inaccuracy are always cursed.</li>
<li>New rings of stealth and loudness, which positively/negatively adjust a player&#8217;s stealth; these take the place of rings of sustenance and hunger.</li>
<li>Followers of good gods no longer get a chance to turn holy enemies neutral.</li>
<li>The Book of War Chants is no more.</li>
<li>Removed spells: Fire Brand, Freezing Aura, Lethal Infusion, Poison Weapon.</li>
<li>Removed enemies: silver stars, flaming corpses, grizzly bears.</li>
</ul>
<p>A brief reminder that the <code>gods</code> experimental branch is still available for testing on <a href="http://crawl.s-z.org">cszo</a> and <a href="http://crawl.beRotato.org:8080">cbro</a>; if you want to help get our newest potential additions to the pantheon into the game, be sure to help us try them out!</p>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-3-may-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.14.1 bugfix release</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-1-bugfix-release</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-1-bugfix-release#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 15:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2694</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers: With the tournament over, here is a new minor release fixing the known bugs that cropped up during the tournament &#8211; 0.14.1: Several crash fixes. Fire dragons correctly grant bonus Dithmenos piety. Ranged attacks from invisibile monsters correctly turn off autopickup. Good gods punish the player properly for negative energy clouds. Natasha no [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers:</p>
<p>With the tournament over, here is a new minor release fixing the known bugs that cropped up during the tournament &#8211; 0.14.1:</p>
<ul>
<li>Several crash fixes.</li>
<li>Fire dragons correctly grant bonus Dithmenos piety.</li>
<li>Ranged attacks from invisibile monsters correctly turn off autopickup.</li>
<li>Good gods punish the player properly for negative energy clouds.</li>
<li>Natasha no longer revives after being pacified, and does not get a new item when reviving.</li>
<li>When playing a race with permanent flight ability, it is now possible to remove an item granting flight over dangerous terrain.</li>
<li>Wanderers do not occasionally get more MP than other backgrounds.</li>
</ul>
<p>Builds for most platforms are now available over at the <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">downloads page</a>.</p>
<p>Happy Crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-1-bugfix-release/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 27 April 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-april-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-april-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 03:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! With the end of the tournament, trunk development is gearing up again. Here are some of the changes that have already been made: A large number of enemy glyphs (for console players) have been changed; see Mantis #8242 for more details. Crypt has been reduced to three levels (was five); the entrance to [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers! With the end of the tournament, trunk development is gearing up again. Here are some of the changes that have already been made:</p>
<ul>
<li>A large number of enemy glyphs (for console players) have been changed; see <a href="https://crawl.develz.org/mantis/view.php?id=8242">Mantis #8242</a> for more details.</li>
<li>Crypt has been reduced to three levels (was five); the entrance to Tomb is always on Crypt:3.</li>
<li>Some areas of the Tomb layout can now vary.</li>
<li>Formicids can no longer throw large rocks.</li>
<li>Tengu gain their permanent flight ability at XL14 (was 15).</li>
<li>Changes/improvements to forms: all non-undead forms can eat and drink normally; all forms can butcher; wisp form can read scrolls and cannot blink innately.</li>
<li>Enemies are more intelligent about using some attack spells such as Symbol of Torment and Chain Lightning when the player is not in LOS.</li>
<li>Manticores can now move as fast as the player.</li>
<li>Komodo dragons bite harder but can no longer sicken the player.</li>
<li>Deep dwarf death knights are now (human) death knights.</li>
<li>Removed enemies: vapours, thorn lotuses, giant goldfish, silver stars.</li>
<li>Dazzling Spray replaces Invisibility in the book of Maledictions (the Enchanter starting spellbook); Invisibility in turn replaces Apportation in the book of Burglary. (Note that each of these spells is still available in at least one other spellbook.)</li>
<li>When the player casts Ozocubu&#8217;s Refrigeration, they are now prevented from using potions for several turns instead of having their potions destroyed.</li>
<li>Damage from the electrocution brand has been reduced slightly.</li>
<li>There are status lights for might, agility, and brilliance.</li>
<li>Followers of good gods no longer get a chance to pacify holy enemies.</li>
<li>The low-level weapon branding skills and the book of War Chants have been removed.</li>
<li>Scrolls of brand weapon can no longer be used to affix brands, and do not trigger a distortion effect on rebranding a distortion weapon.</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, <a href="http://crawl.beRotato.org:8080">crawl.beRotato.org</a> has some experimental branches available for testing: &#8220;ranged_combat&#8221;, containing a mostly-complete rewrite of the system of ranged combat (bows, crossbows, etc.), and &#8220;gods&#8221;, featuring two new deities &#8211; Gozag Ym Sagoz the Greedy and Qazlal Stormbringer. These branches should also be available on <a href="http://crawl.s.z.org/">crawl.s-z.org</a> shortly.</p>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-27-april-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.14 Tournament Results</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament-results</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament-results#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 22:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elliptic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2681</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 0.14 tournament is over. For 16 days, players could compete for tournament points and banners by playing 0.14 games on the public servers. The winning player was Tolias, with 6521 points. Over the course of the tournament Tolias won 18 games, all of them with Nemelex&#8217;s Choice species/background combinations. In second place was johnnyzero, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.14/overview.html" title="0.14 tournament">0.14 tournament</a> is over. For 16 days, players could compete for tournament points and banners by playing 0.14 games on the public servers.</p>
<p>The winning player was <strong>Tolias</strong>, with 6521 points. Over the course of the tournament Tolias won 18 games, all of them with Nemelex&#8217;s Choice species/background combinations. In second place was <strong>johnnyzero</strong>, with 5824 points and 15 wins, including the win with the latest start time. In third place was <strong>Yermak</strong>, with 5534 points and 12 wins, including the first 15-rune win.</p>
<p>The fastest wins in the tournament were achieved by <strong>elliptic</strong> (turncount, 16177 turns with a DDBe) and <strong>simm</strong> (realtime, 1h 16m with a MiBe). <strong>4tharraofdagon</strong> yet again had the highest score, 40M points with a TrMo of Cheibriados. <strong>Basil</strong> had the longest streak, of 7 games. Three Tier III banners were attained by only two players each: Nature&#8217;s Ally, by <strong>Basil</strong> and <strong>Megaslime</strong>; Lord of Darkness, by <strong>jeanjacques</strong> and <strong>joy1999</strong>; and The Heretic, by <strong>jeanjacques</strong> and <strong>Piginabag</strong>. The first victory of the tournament was claimed by <strong>Roarke</strong>, a mere 16 seconds before runner-up <strong>Basil</strong>.</p>
<p>The clan competition was won by <strong>how I learned to stop worrying and lock the vaults</strong> (21281 points). <strong>Aqua Felid</strong> (17973 points) and <strong>Talkin Bout MiGl</strong> (17673 points) were second and third respectively. There were 139 clans in all.</p>
<p>Here are some assorted statistics on the tournament games (with quits removed), compared with the 0.13 tournament (in parentheses):</p>
<pre>
Players with at least one game: 2318 (1771)
Players with at least one game to reach XL 9: 1589 (1129)
Players who got a rune: 787 (528)
Players who won a game: 325 (246)
Total wins: 743 (603)
Win %: 1.31% (1.37%)
Total player time: 35858 hrs (25902 hrs)
Avg player time: 15.5 hrs (14.6 hrs)
Proportion of players using webtiles: 80.4% (76.5%)
Proportion of winners using webtiles: 70.6% (62.6%)
</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament-results/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>CSZO broken</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/cszo-broken</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/cszo-broken#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 14:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dpeg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2658</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Crawlers, This is a very inopportune moment, but it seems that CSZO vanished from the Internet this morning. The maintainer Amethyst opened an emergency ticket with the ISP a few hours ago; there has been no response yet. For the time being, please use CAO or CBRO. If the downtime persists, we will try [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Crawlers,</p>
<p>This is a very inopportune moment, but it seems that CSZO vanished from the Internet this morning. The maintainer Amethyst opened an emergency ticket with the ISP a few hours ago; there has been no response yet.</p>
<p>For the time being, please use <a href="http://crawl.akrasiac.org:8080/" title="crawl.akrasiac.org webtiles" target="_blank">CAO</a> or <a href="http://crawl.berotato.org:8080/" title="crawl.berotato.org webtiles" target="_blank">CBRO</a>. If the downtime persists, we will try to host the tournament page elsewhere until it is resolved.</p>
<p>Update 2014-04-16 14:43 UTC: The ISP says they are having technical difficulty with their fiber connections to two upstream providers, and have been working on the issue since it started about eight hours ago.  Several customers are experiencing problems, not just CSZO.  They expect the network to be &#8220;back up and running soon&#8221;. -neil</p>
<p><strong>Update 2014-04-16 20:55 UTC</strong>: The network is <a href="https://crawl.s-z.org/" title="crawl.s-z.org webtiles" target="_blank">back up</a>, but there is still some packet loss for the time being, so expect some lag until everything is fully resolved. -neil</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/cszo-broken/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crawl 0.14: &#8220;The Shadowy Depths of Madness&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-the-shadowy-depths-of-madness</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-the-shadowy-depths-of-madness#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 16:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are proud to announce the release of Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup 0.14: &#8220;The Shadowy Depths of Madness&#8221; is released! 0.14 features two new races, a new god, a new branch, many new spells, enemies and items, and a wealth of other changes. Download DCSS 0.14 here, or play it online on one of many [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to announce the release of Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup 0.14: &#8220;The Shadowy Depths of Madness&#8221; is released! 0.14 features two new races, a new god, a new branch, many new spells, enemies and items, and a wealth of other changes.</p>
<p>Download DCSS 0.14 <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">here</a>, or <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/howto">play it online</a> on one of many servers across the world!</p>
<p>The release tournament will begin at 20:00 UTC on Friday 11 April, with all online 0.14 games counting towards your score. See the <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.14/">tournament website</a>for more details, including how to set up or join a clan.</p>
<p>0.14&#8242;s highlights include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Characters:</strong> Two new races: Formicids, an insectoid species with permanent stasis and an affinity for digging, and Vine Stalkers, a parasitic plant on a human host &#8211; very fragile, but possessing great regenerative ability, permanent guardian spirit, and a powerful magic-draining bite. Recommended backgrounds and species have been adjusted; in particular, backgrounds can recommend species that don&#8217;t necessarily recommend that background and vice versa (e.g. Chaos Knight -> Troll may be recommended whereas Troll -> Chaos Knight is not). Fighters and Gladiators start with better weapons. Poison damage is now deterministic. </li>
<li><strong>Places:</strong> The lower half of the dungeon has been transformed into a new branch, the Depths; five levels long and containing the entrance to the Realm of Zot. The Vaults require a rune to enter. Ziggurats now require three runes to enter in lieu of an entry fee.</li>
<li><strong>Monsters:</strong> A great deal of new enemies appear, primarily in the Lair sub-branches &#8211; from new specialist nagas to plants with vicious volleys of thorns to demonspawn with a variety of sets of mutations and jobs. Three new uniques make their debut: Natasha, the lost felid familiar of a powerful wizard; Asterion, a powerful minotaur king; and Vashnia, leader of an elite squad of naga sharpshooters. Adjustments have been made to many other enemies.</li>
<li><strong>Gods:</strong> Dithmenos the Shadowed makes a debut, granting followers an aura of shadows and many abilities related thereto. Divine wrath is now contingent on gaining experience; it can no longer be &#8220;waited out&#8221;. Zin and Okawaru no longer care about the deaths of allies.</li>
<li><strong>Spells:</strong>A great deal of spells have been added to the Summoning school, allowing the creation of minions from lightning spires to harpies and sphinxes to your very own spell-casting construct. Glaciate, a level 9 Conjurations/Ice spell, makes its debut as a replacement for Ice Storm; it creates a powerful cone-shaped icy blast that can freeze enemies solid.</li>
<li><strong>Items:</strong> Several new rods have been introduced, from the rod of clouds with its ability to call forth strange and powerful cloud effects at high power to the rod of ignition with great explosive power. Many new pre-defined artefacts are available, and several have received tweaks and modernisation. All scrolls now identify on read.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a list of other major changes, see the <a href="https://gitorious.org/crawl/crawl/blobs/stone_soup-0.14/crawl-ref/docs/changelog.txt">changelog</a>. Many thanks to all those who have <a href="https://gitorious.org/crawl/crawl/blobs/stone_soup-0.14/crawl-ref/CREDITS.txt">contributed</a>to Dungeon Crawl Stone Soup. We hope you enjoy playing 0.14!</p>
<p>(Update 2014-04-10 16:20 UTC: OS X binaries of 0.14.0 are now available from the <a href="/wordpress/downloads">downloads</a> page.  Many thanks to frogor!  -neil)</p>
<p>(Update 2014-04-24 20:36 UTC: Debian/Ubuntu packages in 0.14 are now available! See the <a href="/wordpress/downloads">downloads</a> page for more info. ~Grunt)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-the-shadowy-depths-of-madness/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.13.2 bugfix release</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-13-2-bugfix-release</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-13-2-bugfix-release#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 17:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! In anticipation of the imminent release of 0.14, we&#8217;re happy to announce the final 0.13 release, 0.13.2. Get the source code and Windows builds over at the Downloads page. Check back in a week or so for the final 0.14 release!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers!</p>
<p>In anticipation of the imminent release of 0.14, we&#8217;re happy to announce the final 0.13 release, <b>0.13.2</b>. Get the source code and Windows builds over at the <a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/downloads">Downloads</a> page.</p>
<p>Check back in a week or so for the final 0.14 release!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-13-2-bugfix-release/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>0.14 Tournament</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 15:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elliptic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 0.14 tournament will begin in just one week! From 20:00 UTC Friday 11 April through 20:00 UTC Sunday 27 April, any 0.14 game played on any of the online servers will count for the tournament. 0.14 will be officially released before the start of the tournament &#8211; at the moment, a 0.14 beta is [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 0.14 tournament will begin in just one week! From <strong>20:00 UTC Friday 11 April</strong> through <strong>20:00 UTC Sunday 27 April</strong>, any <strong>0.14 game</strong> played on any of the online servers will count for the tournament. 0.14 will be officially released before the start of the tournament &#8211; at the moment, a 0.14 beta is playable on all the online servers except CDO.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.14/">rules page</a> contains all the details about how to score points and earn banners in the tournament. There are quite a few changes to the banners this tournament.</p>
<p>As usual, clans (teams of up to six players) can be formed and changed until one week into the tournament, so don&#8217;t panic if you aren&#8217;t on one yet! (Being on a clan isn&#8217;t necessary to participate in the tournament, but it can be a lot of fun.)</p>
<p>Once the tournament has started, the <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.14/overview.html">tournament leaderboard</a> will contain the current results. (Before tournament start, some scores might briefly appear on this page as we test the tournament scripts, but they are just for testing.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/0-14-tournament/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A sneak peek at future development</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/a-sneak-peek-at-future-development</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/a-sneak-peek-at-future-development#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 11:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2597</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! For a limited time, we&#8217;re offering an insight into the future of Crawl development. To see the latest and greatest the devteam has to over, check out trunk on http://crawl.s-z.org/ . Happy crawling!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers!</p>
<p>For a limited time, we&#8217;re offering an insight into the future of Crawl development. To see the latest and greatest the devteam has to over, check out trunk on http://crawl.s-z.org/ .</p>
<p>Happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/a-sneak-peek-at-future-development/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crawl Art exhibition now open!</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-art-exhibition-now-open</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-art-exhibition-now-open#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 18:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dpeg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2608</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Inspired by a tavern thread, I realised how much artistic talent goes largely unnoticed! Thankfully, artist baconkid immediately agreed to immortalise some of his work on CDO &#8722; if you haven&#8217;t seen his drawings yet, make sure to dash to the new Crawl Art page Consider yourself a good Crawler if you recognise the content [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by a <a href="https://crawl.develz.org/tavern/viewtopic.php?f=17&amp;t=4204">tavern thread</a>, I realised how much artistic talent goes largely unnoticed! Thankfully, artist <em>baconkid</em> immediately agreed to immortalise some of his work on CDO &minus; if you haven&#8217;t seen his drawings yet, make sure to dash to the new</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="http://arts.crawl.develz.org/"><span style="font-size:250%">Crawl Art page</span></a></strong></p>
<p>Consider yourself a good Crawler if you recognise the content of one or two pictures at once. And a hopeless addict if you get all four. :)</p>
<p>It looks very spartan right now. I would be happy if, over time, more drawings and possibly fan fiction or other art find a home over there. If you want to recommend something for the Crawl Art page, please contact me (private forum message or email). In the long run, we may need to set up an editorial office, but for now this will do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-art-exhibition-now-open/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crawl 0.14 beta and tournament schedule</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-beta-and-tournament-schedule</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-beta-and-tournament-schedule#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 20:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2593</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers! Crawl 0.14 has entered the beta phase; it is now playable on CSZO and CAO, and should be available on other servers soon. Local beta binaries should also be available in the immediate future. The release will most likely occur a day or two before the tournament&#8217;s start date on Friday 11 April [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers!</p>
<p>Crawl 0.14 has entered the beta phase; it is now playable on <a href="http://crawl.s-z.org">CSZO</a> and <a href="http://crawl.akrasiac.org:8080">CAO</a>, and should be available on other servers soon. Local beta binaries should also be available in the immediate future.</p>
<p>The release will most likely occur a day or two before the tournament&#8217;s start date on <b>Friday 11 April 2014 at 20:00 UTC</b>. The tournament will run until <b>Sunday 27 April 2014 at 20:00 UTC</b>.</p>
<p>See also the <a href="http://s-z.org/neil/git/?p=crawl.git;a=blob;f=crawl-ref/docs/changelog.txt;hb=refs/heads/stone_soup-0.14">0.14 changelog</a> and the <a href="http://dobrazupa.org/tournament/0.14/">tournament rules</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/crawl-0-14-beta-and-tournament-schedule/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 22 March 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-22-march-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-22-march-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers &#8211; here are some more changes as we wind down 0.14 development: MR-granting items now grant fixed increments of magic resistance (see the % screen &#8211; there are numbers involved behind the scenes but those exact values aren&#8217;t important). Orbs of destruction don&#8217;t explode if they collide with another orb of destruction before [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers &#8211; here are some more changes as we wind down 0.14 development:</p>
<ul>
<li>MR-granting items now grant fixed increments of magic resistance (see the % screen &#8211; there are numbers involved behind the scenes but those exact values aren&#8217;t important).</li>
<li>Orbs of destruction don&#8217;t explode if they collide with another orb of destruction before travelling more than a short distance (so feel free to abuse those high powered decks of destruction).</li>
<li>The colours of the species/background menu selector have been changed again.</li>
<li>The amount of poisoning dealt by poisonous monster attacks has been adjusted slightly (less for early game enemies, more for late game enemies).</li>
<li>Josephine has a new spell set (and rN+++).</li>
<li>Formicid self-shafting is no longer noisy.</li>
<li>All tiered demon enemies can now open doors.</li>
</ul>
<p>Look forward to news about the release of 0.14 soon, and happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-22-march-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trunk updates, 16 March 2014</title>
		<link>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-16-march-2014</link>
		<comments>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-16-march-2014#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 20:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Play-Testing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/?p=2586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi crawlers &#8211; here&#8217;s another round of last minute tune-ups to 0.14: Formicids can no longer wield giant (spiked) clubs and have slightly adjusted aptitudes. Throwing nets no longer degrade; instead they mulch similar to other projectiles. Fighters start with a potion of might. Swinging a chaos weapon no longer polymorphs or shafts the attacker. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi crawlers &#8211; here&#8217;s another round of last minute tune-ups to 0.14:</p>
<ul>
<li>Formicids can no longer wield giant (spiked) clubs and have slightly adjusted aptitudes.</li>
<li>Throwing nets no longer degrade; instead they mulch similar to other projectiles.</li>
<li>Fighters start with a potion of might.</li>
<li>Swinging a chaos weapon no longer polymorphs or shafts the attacker.</li>
<li>The shopping interface has been simplified.</li>
<li>Spells can be memorised even at 100% failure rate.</li>
<li>Picking up runes in Pandemonium increases the chances of exits being generated.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here&#8217;s to a 0.14 release in the near future &#8211; and happy crawling!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/trunk-updates-16-march-2014/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
